[MUSIC]
欢迎收看斯坦福大学公开课
Stanford University.
本字幕由志愿者义务贡献
>> Okay, well, welcome to Lecture 15 of
欢迎参加斯坦福大学 2015 年冬季学期的
Stanford CS193P Winter of 2015.
CS193P 课程的第15讲。
So my topic slide today, I actually have topics for
这是今天的幻灯片，实际上这些内容是我们这一周两节课
this whole week, the two days.
所要讲的内容。
This is going to be kinda one continuous demonstration.
接着将继续一个 deom 演示
Where I'm going to go back to the demonstration,
deom 演示完成之后，我会在来讲幻灯片上的内容,
back to the slides, back to the demonstration.
然后在再返回继续 deom 演示。
Although today,
至于今天，
I'm probably only going to cover that first slide point.
我估计只能讲完幻灯片上第一部分，
And then, I have a demo pretty much the rest of the way.
接着，剩余的大部分时间我会现场做一个 demo 演示。
If I have time left, which hopefully I do,
如果还有时间剩余，我希望会是这样的，
I will do the slides for the camera.
我会继续讲关于摄像头的部分。
And then, we can start off on Wednesday with the camera part
这样的话，我们周三就可以直接开始摄像头的 demo 演示，
of the demo and then move on to the rest of the stuff.
然后再接着讲下面的内容。
But, it's pretty action-packed.
嗯，是挺令人激动的。
I have a lot of stuff to cover,
我有很多东西需要讲，
especially in today's demo.
特别是今天的 demo 。
It's gonna be a lot more even than just modal and
将包括很多内容，不仅仅是 model segue (模态segue)
popover segues.
和 popover segue（弹出框segue）。
I'm gonna talk a little bit more about notifications and
我也会加一些 notification 和 adaptations
adaptations, things like that.
方面的内容。
So there's a lot to cover.
对，有很多内容呢。
All right so I'm going to dive in here though with modal
我将从 modal view controllers 开始，
view controllers and I intentionally put off
我是故意将 modal segue（模态segue）
the modal segues until towards the end of the quarter.
放到了这个学期的最后才讲。
Because when people see it early, they're like, oh, wow,
因为如果你早知道了它，你就会，哇
I'm just gonna put everything up modally.
我可以在任何地方都用它来搞定。
It's just so easy to do a modal segue.
modal segue（模态segue）用起来非常简单。
And it is easy to do a modal segue.
对的，modal segue用起来非常方便。
But it actually has to be used with care because since it
但是实际上用起来要非常小心，如果用的时候一旦锁住屏幕，
locks up, you're out,
你就完了，
basically until they deal with what's on-screen.
基本上，modal segue（模态segue）主要是用来处理屏幕上的内容。
The users can kinda be a little bit disturbed by modal.
用户有时反而会被它给弄迷糊了。
Generally users prefer more free flowing thing where they
一般来说，用户更愿意见到的情况是
can click on something and then move back and
点击一个地方，就能返回。
things you know, flow a little better.
这样会更好。
But there are sometimes when it just doesn't make sense for
但是有时候，你的APP不允许这样，
your app to proceed without stopping the user and
必须要求用户回答一个问题之后，
making them answer a question.
才能正常跳转。
So modal view controllers is what that's good for.
这时，modal view controller 就是派这个用场的。
We've already seen modal view controllers, actually.
实际上，我们已经见过 modal view  controller 了。
The alerts, the whole alert and action sheet thing.
alert ，整个 alert 和 action sheet 包括在一起。
That's nothing more than a UIViewController
它们就是一个 UIViewController 。
that we put up modally.
我们将其设置为模态化。
Notice that it took over the screen, didn't let us do
注意到，它在屏幕上之后，除非我们点击了之后，
anything until we responded to the alert of the action seat.
否则我们不能操作其它任何东西。
And modal view controllers are just creating your own
modal view controller 就是创建了你自己创建的 View Controller
things that pop up and
并且弹出的屏幕上，
don't let the user proceed until you deal with it.
它要求用户必须响应，否则不允许进行其他任何的操作。
So here's an example of a modal view controller.
这里有一个 modal view controller 的例子。
Here, I'm in the contacts app.
这里，我在联系人的 app 里。
And if I tap on that little plus in the corner,
如果你点击右上角的的加号，
it's gonna put up a modal MVC.
这里就会出现一个模态的 MVC.
So I'll tap on it, then modal MVC slides up from the bottom.
接着我点击一下，这个模态的 MVC就从底部滑动出来。
This is an MVC that lets you add a new contact.
这个 MVC 让你增加一个新的联系人。
And so that's something that you wanna kinda get it all
这样，你就可以继续
the way you want.
你想做的。
And say, okay, add it,
就是说，好，加一个，
rather than it being kinda partially added all the time.
我们是不会一直都需要增加新的联系人。
So that's why they use modal here.
所以我们这里用模态对话框。
Although, you could probably even think of a way to do this
尽管，你也可以想到不用模态对话框
non-modally.
的方法。
But it's not bad.
但是，这个方法其实不错呀。
Now notice that there's no back button per se.
注意下，这里是没有返回按钮的。
But a lot of times where the back
但是大多数时候，我们
button usually would be is a cancel button, okay.
看到的返回按钮就是取消按钮，
Which will take them back,
一样可以让我们回去，对的！
but it will cancel whatever they're doing in this
这样的话，在模态对话框里，你所做的操作，
modal view controller.
都不会被保存。
And then, often, in the upper right, there is a button,
嗯，一般情况下，在右上角，这里都会有一个按钮，
a done button, or save button, or something like.
done，或是 save ，或是什么其他名字的。
That will usually commit the changes in the modal
用来提交我们的内容，
view controller, and then dismiss it, okay.
然后将当前视图从当前的显示中移除。
Now, this particular modal view controller actually
现在，一个单独的 modal view controller 也是可以
can put another modal view controller up.
被放在另一个 modal view controller 的上面。
If you look at this button here,
大家看下这个按钮，
add photo, if you click on it,
add photo，你点击一下它，
it's going to put another modal view controller up.
将会出现另外一个 modal view controller 。
It slides up from the bottom,
从底部滑出来。
asking you to pick a photo from your photo library here.
让你从你的相册种选择一张照片，
I don't have any photos so I couldn't do it.
我现在没有照片，所以没法选。
There's no back button here because you
这里是没有返回按钮的，因为你必须选择一张照片，
either pick a photo or you cancel.
或是你不选。
Okay, so you don't need a dumb button.
对吧，你不需要一个没用的按钮。
I would have argued that that cancel button,
我认为过这里的取消按钮，
I kind of feel like should be on the left.
应该是在左边的。
This is an Apple app, so I guess I'm wrong.
不过这是苹果的官方 App ，所以我想应该是我错了。
But to me I'm always,
但对于我来说，
kinda looking to the upper left for get me out of here,
我一直认为左上角应该有一个按钮，让我离开，
get me back to what I was before, but anyway.
返回到我之前的页面。
So if we do hit that cancel button you can see that this
这里，我点击取消按钮，你可以看到
modal view controller then will dismiss, and
modal view controller 就会被移除了，然后就可以看到
the other one comes back.
之前的 View Controller。
And same thing here.
同样的，
Once we're done in here let's say we Cancel or we hit Done,
一旦我们点击了 done ，结果也是
either way.
一样的。
And then, this one will dismiss and
也是，当前的内容会被移除，返回
it goes back to where you were.
之前的页面。
So that's the way modal view controllers work.
这就是 modal view controoler 的工作方式。
They just take over the screen, you do something and
它们出现在屏幕上，你进行了一些操作之后，它们
then when they're done they dismiss.
就会被移除。
Now there's a lot of different ways for
modal view controller有很多种
modal view controllers to appear on the screen visually.
不同展现在屏幕上的方式。
And we will talk about that.
后面我们会谈到。
So as I said, you want to be careful with these.
不过我要说，你必须要小心使用它们。
They do block your UI,
它们会阻止你的 UI 响应，
it will be completely only doing this one thing.
你只能完成modal view controller 的处理之后，才能继续。
Again, sometimes that's what you want.
当然，有些时候，这就是你想要的。
But don't jump to modal view controllers as your at first
但是，当你需要将你的 MVC 展示到屏幕上时，不要将modal view controller
solution to every time you want to put an MVC on screen.
作为你的第一选择。
You got navigation controllers,
你可以使用 navigation controller，
you got split views, you got tab bars, stuff like that,
你可以使用 split view ，你可以使用 tab bar 这些方法，
those are usually better solutions if possible.
通常，这些都是更好的解决方案。
All right, so how do we set up a modal segue?
好吧，那我们如何设置一个 modal segue ？
Very, very simple.
非常非常简单。
You've got your storyboard, well,
你已经有了 storyboard ，
sometimes you'll get a MVC, like the alert MVC in code,
你有一个 MVC , 比如一个 Alert MVC ，
and you put it up with that present view controller.
你想把它放到你当前展示的 View Controller 上面。
And I'll talk about that here in a second.
我下面马上就会讲到这个。
But if you're doing your own MVC,
但如果你需要处理的是你自己创建的 MVC ,
usually it's in your storyboard, you've built
通常是在你的 storyboard 里的 MVC ,
the MVC that you want to put up modally in there.
你会希望以模态的形式展示。
And then you just Ctrl + drag to it.
这样你只需要按住Ctrl通过拖拽就可以完成。
But instead of saying, show or show detail,
不过这次不选择 show 或者 show detail，
you say present modally, okay?
而是选择 present modally ，懂了吗？
And that's just gonna make your MVC appear on screen and
这就可以让你的 MVC 以模态的形式展现屏幕上，
take over and it's as simple as that.
就这么简单。
You can inspect the segue.
你可以检查一下这个 segue 。
Anytime you make a segue you can always inspect it
你任何时候都可以检查 segue，
to set the style of segue modal,
并且将它的类型设置为 modal
or push, or you know, the shows, or whatever.
或是 push ，或是其他的，比如 show 之类的。
And you can also inspect the style or presentation of
同时你也可以看到 modal 下的不同展示样式
modal, which we'll show you in a second as well.
我后面也会展示给你们看的。
So, if you need to present a modal view controller,
好了，如果你需要展示一个 modal view controller ，
not from a button, so you want some other action.
但不是通过一个按钮 ， 你希望通过其他的 action ，
Like, for example, you had a map view and
举个例子，你有一个 map view 然后，
you wanted a call-out button to do a modal thing,
你希望有一个 Call-out（呼出）按钮，实现模态的对话框，
which is what we're gonna do today.
顺便说下，这就是我们今后后面需要做的，
Then you can perform segue from code.
然后你可以在代码里直接调用 segue 。
You already know how to do that.
你应该已经知道怎么做了，
Or if you actually have the view controller in your hand,
或是你已经有了一个 view controller,
you got it cuz it's an alert view controller.
比如你已经有了一个 alert view controller。
Or when we do the camera we're gonna understand that
或是一个摄像头的 view controller ，后面我们会讲到关于摄像头的使用，
the camera thing gives us a view controller.
它其实返回给我们的也是一个 view controller 。
We can actually present the view controller using present
我们都可以将这些 View Controller
view controller.
直接展示出来。
Same way that we did alerts.
和我们处理 alert 的方式是一样的。
And that's just going to present it.
接着我们就要把它展示出来。
How it's presented is actually determined by a property
具体如何展示实际上时取决于当前已经在展示的 view controller
on the view controller that's being presented.
上属性设置。
So a view controllers gets to say,
所以这个view controller 会被告诉说，
here's how I want to be presented modally, okay.
我是希望用这种样式的以模态的形式展示出来。
And that property is called modalPresentationStyle and
这里我们把这个属性叫做 modalPresentationStyle ，同时，它是
it's an enumerated type.
一个枚举类型。
And here are some of the examples here, FullScreen,
这里有一些例子，比如 FullScreen（全屏），
which is the default,
它是默认值，
where it just comes up over the entire screen.
意思是出现的时候是占满整个屏幕的。
There's OverFullScreen, which is full screen, but
这里还有一个 OverFullScreen ，也是占满整个屏幕，
it doesn't block out what's underneath.
但它并不阻止下面的屏幕互动。
Okay, so things show through,
好的，通过这样的操作，
the thing that is coming up on top of shows through.
现在将内容在最上方展示出来了，
Now you can't interact with those things behind cause
而你不能和它下面的元素进行交互的原因是，
you're modal but they do show through.
因为你是一个模态的。
And then of course a .Popover is essentially,
接着，还有一个是 popover 。
a modal presentation style cause a popover takes over
这种模式态的展示样式，是一个在屏幕上弹出一个
the screen also.
窗口。
It just dimis out the rest, you're working in your popover
它刚好盖住了原来的内容，你只能在你弹出的区域内进行交互。
if you click anywhere else it makes the popover go away.
如果你点击其他地方，弹出出来的页面就会被移除。
There's some other ones, like form sheet,
这里还有一些其他的，比如 sheet ，
which I'll show you in the demo today for on the iPad.
今天我们会在 iPad 上演示这个 demo 。
Sometimes you want to present something but
有时，你想展示一些内容，
you don't want it to be gigantic,
但你又不希望它们太大，
filling the whole screen,
以至于占据整个屏幕，
you want it to be a little smaller.
你希望它能够小一点儿。
So we'll show you how to do that.
我会告诉你怎么做到的。
You prepare for a modal segue exactly like any other segue.
你需要准备一个 modal segue ，和其他的 segue 一样就可以。
I didn't even put in any yellow on this slide,
我并没有在幻灯片上做什么特别的标记。
it's just normal code, there's nothing special there.
都是一些很平常的代码，没有什么特别的。
Some people ask the question a lot,
有一个问题被问了很多次，
well how do I hear back from my modally segued to MVC.
就是我怎么样才能通过 modally segued 返回到 MVC 。
So like, in the contacts for example, I added a contact.
就像在联系人这个例子中，我增加了一个联系人。
Well when the contact is added,
当联系人增加了之后，
how does it communicate back to me, here's the contact.
是如何返回给我，这是一个联系人。
Well, actually the MVC that put that contact adding thing
好吧，实际上， MVC 增加一个联系人的时候，
up, is probably sharing a model with the other one.
是与其他的“部件”共享了一个模型（model），
Which is to say, the database of contact.
比如，就是一个联系人的数据库。
So when you hit, add contact and you hit done,
所以当你点击，增加一个联系人之后，点击done（保存），
it probably just puts it in the database, okay.
其实只是将这个内容存到数据库了，理解？
So it doesn't really need to communicate back.
所以这里并不需要一个反馈。
But if it did need to communicate back,
但如果你确实需要一个反馈，
the way you would do that is Unwind.
你需要通过 Unwind 这种方式来获得。
Okay.
好了。
Remember the unwinding segues?
还记得 unwinding segue ？
You would just make the done button or whatever in your
在你的模态对话框里加了一个done（保存）按钮之类的
modal thing, Ctrl+drag it up to that little exit button.
然后按住Ctrl后将这个按钮拖动到这个exit（退出）按钮上面。
You define the special storyboard ID action thing and
给这个Action定义一个storyboard ID，然后你就
you would unwind.
可以 unwind（返回）。
And that's how you would communicate back.
这样你就可以实现得到反馈了。
A lot of times though modally presented view controllers
大多数情况下，以模态展示的View Controller，
they do what they do and then you just dismiss them.
完成了他们的“工作”之后，它们就会移除自己。
Because either they're editing this stuff in real time or
这是因为它们都是在实时的修改模型（Model）的内容或是
they are sharing the model so
其他共享的模型（model）
they can edit the model directly.
所以，它们是可以直接编辑模型（model）。
So then they'll just dismiss themselves.
然后它们可以直接移除自己。
So dismissing without doing anything or
在移除的时候不需要任何反馈（回）
unwinding is pretty much the way that Modally segued to
大多数情况下，模态的segue都是这样
controllers come off screen.
来移除自己的。
So how do you dismiss it?
那怎样移除呢？
Well if you unwind it automatically dismisses.
如果你使用unwind的话，就会自动移除，
As you know,
这个你已经知道了。
unwind always includes a dismissal of whatever
unwind 通常是将当前的内容移除之后，
your controller is being unwound from.
然后返回到指定的Controller上。
But if you're not unwinding, then you're going to call
但如果你不用使用 unwind 的话，你就需要主动调用
dismissViewControllerAnimated which takes
dismissViewControllerAnimated这个方法了，
the boolean whether you're gonna animate the dismissal,
你可以设置在移除的时候是否需要动画效果。
which you're always gonna do, pretty much.
多数情况下，你都会选择有动画效果的。
And this is sent to the presenting view controller.
接着就返回到原来的 View Controller（弹出MVC的MVC)。
The view controller that presents you.
你就可以看到l。
'Kay? That is the thing
懂了吗？这就是说
that is responsible for dismissing you.
你要负责手动移除了。
Now if you accidentally send this to the presented
如果你将它设置为被展示的 View Controller，
view controller it's gonna forward it on to its
它就会展示在你当前的 View Controller
presenting view controller.
上面。
Although it can be a little confusing if
这里可能会有点疑惑的地方，
you have a presented view controller that, itself, has
如果你当前正在展示着一个 view Controller ，然后它上面还有
presented another one and you say dismiss view controller.
另一个被展示的，而你这时移除 View Controller。
Well, do you mean to dismiss the thing it presented?
那你是想移除被展示的
Or dismiss from the thing it was presenting?
还是弹出展示的？
So that's why with the rule is, the presenting
对此，有一个规则，移除视图只针对
view controller is the one you should send this dismiss to.
当前正在展示的（用户可以看到的）View Controller 。
So I, personally, think it's wrong code for
而我个人觉得，如果你对一个不在展示状态的 view controller
you to send dismiss view controller to the presented
进行移除的话，本身就是不对的。
view controller expecting it to dismiss itself.
除非是它自己移除它自己。
'Kay?
懂了吗？
The presented view controller can get its
一个被弹出View Controller 在任何时候都可以有方法得到
presenting view controller at any time with the method, or
当初“弹出”它的View Controller 。或通过得到这个“弹出”它的
the variable, presenting view controller.
view controller 这个变量。
Okay, every view controller that's being presented
也就是输，任何一个被“弹出”的view controller 都是知道
knows it's presenting view controller and
是谁“弹出”自己的这个view controller，
then it can just send this message to it.
然后也是可以给它发送消息的。
So we'll see that in the code of the demo as well.
我们后面的 demo 中也有这部分的代码。
So how does the modal view controller appear onscreen?
如何将一个模态的view controller 展示到屏幕上？
You've seen it slide up from the bottom, right?
你已经看到它是从下面滑动上来的，对吧？
That's the default modal transition style,
这是默认的模态式的过渡效果，
which is called cover vertical.
我们称之为 "cover vertical"。
And you, again, the view controller that's being
接着，这个View Controller被“弹”出屏幕上，
presented gets to say how it wants to appear on screen.
就像你所希望的那样。
And so this is different than, you know, the modal style,
至于区别，在模态的样式上
like form sheet or something like that.
比如需要提交的表单或是其他。
This is how the animation happens, 'kay?
这里就可以通过动画效果，
How the actual transmission happens.
完成实际的过渡。
And so, again,
另外，
there's another property in the view controller that's
在view controller 里还有另外一个属性，
being presented called Modal Transition Style.
叫做 Modal Transition Style 。（出现或离开的样式）
And cover vertical's the default,
默认值是 Cover Vertical ，
means slide up from the bottom.
就是说从屏幕到底部滑上来。
There's also flip horizontal, which will just flip over.
另外还有 flip horizontal ，翻转的效果。
Okay, take from the old, the view that's presenting view
好的，一个弹出的view controller 和
controller and the presented view controller,
一个被弹出的 view controller 。
we'll flip over and exchange places.
我们将会通过翻转的形式来交换他们的位置，完成过渡转换。
There's also cross dissolve where they'll fade out and
这里还有 Corss dissolve ，意思是一个淡出，
the other one will fade in.
另外一个淡入。
There's even partial curl where the bottom corner
这里还有一个 Partial curl ，意思是从底下一个角
will kind of curl up and show the new view controller.
翻起来，然后展示出一个新的 View Controller 。
That one's a little interesting there because
这里有个很有意思的事情，
once you've done that one, you can't do any more
就是你可以选择任意一种样式，
modal transitions because it would make no sense.
因为实际上它们的意义时相同的。（只是样式不同而已）
You've got this curled up kind of look and then you
你可以看到前面一个View Controller 被卷起，
plant something on top of it, that just breaks the illusion
然后在上面展示内容，就好像
of this being just a little piece of curled thing that
将内容卷起来了一些
lifts up to show you this modally presented thing.
以模态（式）的形式展示给你内容，
Obviously the partial curls gonna be small view
很明显，这种形式更适合那种比较小（面积）的
controllers showing.
view controller的展示。
It's kind of a fun one though sometimes like in the Maps app
这个很有意思，比如在 地图 APP 里，
if you want to set some setting, so
如果你想做一些设置，
turn traffic on, it'll just curl up the map a little bit,
比如打开交通状况，就会在地图的下面卷起一个小角，
you set your settings, and it curls it back down.
你设置完了之后，就会再“压”回去。
Okay?
对吧？
So kind of fun though.
挺有意思的。
All right, so the demo I'm gonna do today it's gonna show
好了，今天我要做的 demo ，将包括前面所有的内容，
you all this stuff, modals, segues, all this stuff.
包括， modals 、 segues 等等。
It's probably gonna take us most of the rest of
我估计我们后面大部分时间都是在
the time here.
做这个 demo。
And I'll try to cover a lot of other things along the way.
我会尽量覆盖我们今天所有学到的内容，
I'm gonna start out by doing some draggable MK annotations.
我们先从做一个可以拖动的 MK  annotations（注释）开始。
I'm also gonna talk much more about notifications cuz,
我也会讲不少关于通知（notifications）的内容。
really, the only notification we did so
是的，我们现在才开始考虑到
far was where we notified ourself.
通知（notification）这个内容。
So I'm gonna show you
我还会给你展示
a little more sophisticated notification where system,
一些复杂一点的
another object is notifying us.
系统通知，
Then I'm gonna go back and cover pop-overs some more.
然后我们再继续 pop-over 这些内容。
We covered a little bit back, way back when, in psychologist
我们会讲各种返回，在psychologist 这个项目里。
but we're gonna do a little more sophisticated popovers.
但我们会做一些更复杂的 popovers 。
We're also going to talk more about adaptive behavior,
我们也会继续讲一些关于设备的适配。
which is to say when you have a modal segue happening,
也就是说当你有一个 modal segue,
what if it's on an iPhone versus an iPad?
它分别在iPhone 和 iPad 上各自是怎么展现的？
It doesn't always wanna look exactly the same.
有些时候是会有不同的展现方式的。
And so we're actually gonna get involved in making it look
所有这些内容我们都会讲到，了解他们是如何
how we want.
实现的。
And as part of that I'm going to show you another thing that
另外，我还有内容要你们讲一下，
I don't have any slides on but it's very easy to use called,
因为它比较简单，所以我就没写到幻灯片上，
which is visual effects.
这个内容就是 visual effects （视觉效果）。
So there's a way to get visual effects,
有很多种不同的 visual effects （视觉效果）
like blurs and vibrancy, things like that.
比如 blurs 和 vibrancy ，类似这些的。
So I'll show you that.
我也会给你们展示。
So you can see, a lot of stuff to go through here.
今天你会看到有很多内容。
And if we have time,
如果我们还有时间，
we'll get back and do through the slides and the camera.
我们还会来继续看有关摄像头这部分的幻灯片。
All right so we're gonna go back to Tracks and
好，我们现在回到 Tracks 这个项目上来，
what we're gonna do here in Trax is we are going to make
我们看下，如果我们准备 Tracks 增加一个自己定义的 Waypoints的话，
it so we can add our own Waypoints.
我们该怎么做。
Right now, Tracks just opens up the GPS file and
现在，Tracks 只是打看一个 GPS 文件，然后
shows you the Waypoints.
将waypoints展示给你。
And I'll show you,
我要给你展示的是，
remind us what that looks like in case we've forgotten.
先给大家看下这个项目吧，以免你们有人忘了它的样子。
All right. Here's our Tracks.
好的，这就是 Tracks 。
And it shows us these nice waypoints down here.
它上面标志了一些 waypoints（航点）。
And we have a nice image over here, and we have this little
在上面还有一些图片，并且有一些按钮
button, disclosure button, which will show us the image
disclosure 按钮，点击这个按钮后，我们可以到
in more detail where we can scroll around.
进一步的详细内容。
Well, what we're gonna do now is make it so
现在，如果我们长按的话，
that if we long press, in other words, we press and
长按的意思就是按住，然后保持不放开，
hold, it's gonna drop a pin there for us.
这样，会有一个小的标志“钉”我们的放的位置
And then we're going to be able to set
我们将给这个小东西加一个名称，
the little thing like Valley Floor there,
比如Valley Floor,或是
or the views are spectacular even from here.
一些美景之类的。
We'll be able to set that for our thing.
我们能够自己设置这些内容。
And we'll even be able to set an image once we learn
在我们后面学了有关摄像头的内容之后，
about how to do the camera next time.
我们还可以设置图片。
But in order to make this work I'm actually gonna change our
但为了让我们能做到，我实际上稍微做了一点改动，
track slightly, which is right now to see this image in more
现在只有点击进入详情之后才可以看到图片，
detail, I press on this little detail disclosure button.
点击这个小小的展示详情按钮（Detail disclosure button）才能。
I'm gonna change it so that you click on the image itself.
我会改成你点击这个图片自己，就能看到
To see the image in more detail so that I can free this
更多的详细内容，这样我就很方便了，
up to be our, we just added a user waypoint and
可以直接加一个航点（waypoint） ，
now we want to edit it, button.
如果想编辑它，需要一个编辑按钮。
'Kay? So this is gonna be our
懂了？这将是一个可以被编辑的 waypoint，
editable user waypoint editing button.
通过这个编辑按钮。
So I'm gonna make that change real quick.
接着我会先快点的把这个需求完成，
So let's go ahead and do that.
好了，我们开始吧。
That's really easy to do, it turns out.
这个其实很容易做的，打开项目。
Right now when we build our callout view right here.
现在我们先创建一个这里需要被调出的 View 。
'Kay? Here's a view for annotation?
对吧？这是一个注释的 View 。
Okay? Here's where we
好了，这就是我们需要
build our callout accessory views.
创建的被调用的详细 View（视图）。
Instead of using a UIImage view to build it,
之前我们是用一个 UIImage View 实现的，这次我们
I'm just gonna make it be a UIButton.
使用 UIButton 来实现。
'Kay?
懂了？
Now, of course, once I make it a UIButton, I also have to
当然，一旦我用了 UIButton ，我也不得不
make sure that I load this UIButton up properly, so
确保这个 UIButton 可以被正确的加载，
I'm gonna go down here to div select annotation view,
所以我觉得决定先听一下去选择一个 注释的视图，
which is where we currently load up that left callout
这个注释视图在被弹出之后，就是会被
access review.
展示的。
I'm gonna change this from being a thumbnail image view
我这里会先把这个缩略图（Image View）改成一个 缩略图的
to calling it the thumbnail ImageButton
图片式按钮（Image Button）。
because it's an image button now instead of an image view.
将 Image View 替换成了 Image Button 。
And of course it's not a UIImageView here, it's a UIButton.
当然了，这里就不是一个UIImageView，而是一个 UIButton 。
And then the only other thing is you don't set a buttons
这里还有一件事事情你需要做，这样就能让你的按钮看起来
image by saying dot image equals image.
和图片是一样似的。
You call a method actually called SetImage.
你需要调用一个方法叫做 SetImage 。
Image.
Image 。
And it has, for state, because the button has various states,
因为按钮有很多种不同的状态，所以这里需要指定状态（state），
highlighted states, other kind of states, but we're just
聚焦状态（highlighted states），以及一些其他的状态，但我们
gonna set it for the normal state of the button.
这里只要设置一个正常的状态（Normal state）就可以了。
So that's the only change I need to make
这里我重要做这一个改变就
to make this work.
可以了。
So let's go take a look at this and
然后我们再过来看下这个能够展示
here we can comment out now our little
详细内容的这个
right callout detail thing.
展示详情按钮。
We don't need that.
我们已经不需要了。
Bring it back in second here.
直接把它们放到后面就好。
But here's our things.
但这里还有件问题。
And so now here when we click it notice we don't have
就是我们现在点击之后，没有了按钮之后
the detailed disclosure on there anymore cuz I commented
我们也无法从右面“呼唤”出
that out right here.
详细的页面。
But this is now a button so
不过现在它已经是一个按钮了，
if I click it now I get to see my image, okay?
所以当我点击的话，我就应该可以看到我们的图片了，对吧？
So I haven't changed the functionality of my app at
到现在我们还有在APP里改过代码，
all, I just kind of moved it to be click on here as
我们只是移动了之后，让它变成可以被点击
opposed to having the detailed disclosure.
取代了原来的展示详情按钮。
Okay, everybody cool?
好了，对这个内容，
With that.
大家都理解了？
All right.
好的。
So, now we've done that.
我们现在已经做好了。
Now let's make it so that if I long press,
接着让我们来处理“长按”的问题。
which means press and hold, it drops a new pin, okay.
也就是说点击后，然后保持，这里将会“钉”住一个小标志。
So how do I do that?
我们该怎么做？
I'm just going to go to my storyboard here.
我们先回到 storyboard 。
And in my storyboard,
在我的 storyboard 里，
I'm going to add a long press gesture to my map view, here.
我将在我的map view里增加一个长按的手势。
So let's go down here, pull this up.
好了，让我们来看，把这个拉上去。
I'm gonna search for, long press.
我来搜一下 long press 。
There it is, right there.
找到了，就在那里。
So I'm just going to drag this gesture out onto my map
我讲把这个手势直接拖到我的
view, okay.
map view 上。
You can see that it appears over here in my
你能在大纲视图下看到我们刚刚增加的
document outline.
手势
Now let's bring up the code.
然后，让我们来看下代码怎么处理。
Okay, I'll put this right here in the waypoints
好的，我们先找到 waypoints（航点） 的对应的部分，
section right here.
对，就是这里。
So I'm going to control drag from this long press gesture
让我要从长按这个手势上 按住 ctrl 拖到
into here.
这里。
It's going to be gesture.
拖过来的将是一个手势。
I'm going to call it addWaypoint.
我给它命名为 addwaypoint 。
It's what it does.
就是这么做的。
It's got the long press gesture as the argument here.
这里有一个参数是 长按的手势。
All right, so there's that.
对的，就是这样。
Let's go back here.
然后我们回到 stroyboard 。
Let's go up to here, okay.
对，我们继续，可以吧。
So here is, where is that?
这是，在哪里？
Here it is.
在这里。
This is the thing I just added,
这就是我刚才加的。
this LongPressGesture right here.
这个长按的手势就在这里。
So what do we need to do inside
那我们需要在这个 LongPressGesture 方法
of this LongPressGesture?
里写些什么呢？
Really not a whole lot to do.
其实没有太多的要写的。
I'm gonna say if the sender.state,
我这里要写 if sender.state 就可以了。
that's the state of the gesture, basically.
这个状态是指手势的状态。
If that equals UIGestureRecognizerState.began,
如果等于 UIGestureRecognizeState.began
now I could do this when this long press starts,
就是长按时间开始，
which is, I'm doing.
也就是，我正在长按。
Or I could do it when the long press ends.
或是我也可以等长按结束之后来处理。
And long pressed by the way, you'll get changed, also,
同时，在长按事件中，如果你保持长按的时候向下移动
as you hold it down, you'll get a change happening.
也会有一个change的事件。
But I like to do it when I began,
不过我愿意当一发生的时候就处理，
because I want instant feedback.
因为我想要及时的反馈。
The user holds the long press,
用户长按的时候，
as soon as it's recognized as a long press and begins, boom,
刚刚长按的时候，就能被识别，很快，
we're gonna drop that pin down there.
我就准备在这里“钉”一个小的标志。
So they don't have to hold their finger any longer and
他们并不需要将手指长按的状态保持太长时间，
they don't have to hold it down and
也不需要在保持长按的时候下移一下
say, hm, where's that, nothings happening.
然后说，看，什么都没有嘛。
Okay, so that's why I decided to do it on began here.
这样，我决定在一开始的就处理。
And to create one we need the coordinates that they clicked
然后根据在他们点击的位置，我们创建一个坐标
on, right, or that they long pressed, they held down.
对，就是他们长按的地方。
We need to find out the CL location coordinate 2D.
我们需要得到这个坐标。
Where in the world they just did that.
在真实的世界中，他们的坐标。
And to do that we're going to use this method in map view
然后我将用Map View里的一个叫 converPoint的方法，这个方法
called convertPoint, which takes a point, so
可以传入一个 Point 对象，然后
let's get the location of the gesture in the map view's
可以让我们得到用户在屏幕上点击的坐标，对应在 Map View 里的坐标系
coordinate systems, okay.
中对应的坐标。
And it converts it to the coordinate system of any view
这个方法可以帮助你在任何视图中转化坐标系。
you want.
这个方法可以帮助你在任何视图中转化成你想要的坐标系。
Which we're going to actually convert it the mapView's
在这里我们实际是希望将其转为地图视图的
coordinate system which is not much of a conversion, okay.
坐标系下，这是一个的转换。
So that creates a view.
接着我们创建一个视图。
So we've converted this gesture to this coordinate
因为我们已经将手势的坐标转换为地图视图下的坐标，
in the mapView, so now we have a CL location coordinate 2D,
所以我们现在得到了2D坐标系下的 CL 位置。
here I'll click on this so
这里我点击一下，可以看到这是
you can see that's a CLLocationCoordinate2D,
CLLocationCoordinate2D 。
that's where the person pressed down.
也就是在用户按下的位置，
So now I'm just gonna create the waypoint, and we can
我可以直接创建一个 waypoint ，然后我们
create the waypoint using GPX waypoint, it only has one
就可以使用GPX的waypoint类来创建了，它只有一个构造方法，
constructor which is the latitude and the longitude.
需要传入经度和纬度。
Okay, so now we've created a waypoint.
好了，现在我们已经创建了一个 waypoint 。
Maybe we'll set some things in the waypoint, like the name.
我们也可以设置其他的一些信息，比如名称。
We just dropped this, so
我们就是要放在这里的，因此
I'm going to call this the waypoint dropped, okay.
因此这个 waypoint 叫做 dropped 。
And then let's just add this annotation
接着，我们给这个 map view 加上
to the map view, okay.
annotation  。
So that's all we need to do to drop something on there.
所以我们需要做的就是在这里放一些内容，
So let's go take a look at that.
那让我们先看一下。
All right, so here's all our points.
对的，这里是我们所有的标志点。
And I'm just gonna long press, you see it dropped one there.
然后当我长按之后，你就会看到这里会增加一个。
And if I click on it, it says, dropped.
然后当我点击的时候，看到这里写着，dropped 。
Now, I don't have any image associated with.
现在，我们还没有与之关联的图片。
I don't have any little sub-information info
在这里也没有任何相关的内容。
field on here.
So, we need to make it so that it does that.
我们需要增加这些内容。
But first, I'm going to make it so
不过，首先我们需要让它
that this can be dragged.
变成可以拖拽的。
Because what if I dropped it here, and
因为当你在这里放置之后，
then I looked in here closer and I was like,
我可以把地图放大，可以看的更清楚一些。
oh no I wanted to drop it on the other side of that road.
哦，我想把它拖到这条路的另外一边，
Okay, I can't pick it up.
但我现在不能拖动。
So I'd like to be able to pick this thing up and move it.
所以我想可以能让它在地图拖动，
So what do we need to do that?
我们要怎么样才能做到呢？
That's very simple as well, we just need to make,
这个也非常简单，我们只需要回到这里，
back here remember, here's our extension to GPX waypoint that
记得吗，这时我们的 GPX 的 Waypoint 的 extension ，
we extended so that it would be an MK annotation.
我们为让他可以作为 MK annotation 而进行的扩展（继承）。
We just need to make this note be a get only,
我们当时将它设置为只读。
it needs to be set and get.
现在需要设置为可以读也可以写。
That's really the only thing you need to do to make
只需要这么做，它就可以变成
something be draggable.
可以拖动的了。
Now, I'm gonna do that in a separate subclass here.
这里，我将会在写一个单独的子类，
I'm gonna call it EditableWaypoint, okay,
我给它起名为 Editablepoint ，
it's a subclass of GPX.Waypoint.
它是 GPX.Waypoint 的子类。
And all it's going to do is override that var coordinate,
我们就是为了重载变量 coordinate 。
and it's perfectly fine to override a var
在子类里重载一个var型的变量是完全没有问题的，
in a subclass to turn it into set and get.
然后可以将其设置为可以读也可以写。
So the get is just gonna return supers version of this,
这里get的方法直接返回super的就可以。
okay.
好了。
And our set, all I'm gonna do on my set, is I'm going to set
至于set方法，我们将实现自己的set方法，我将设置
my latitude equal to the new values latitude.
原来的维度为 newValue 的维度值。
And I'm gonna set my longitude,
同时我们也设置原来的经度值等于
equal to the new values longitude.
newValue 的 经度值
Okay, and remember that latitude and longitude,
好了，记住这里维度值和经度值，
these are just properties in GPX waypoints, okay.
它们是作为 GPX waypoints 类的属性。
Well it has links, you know,
其他还有比如 links，
to our thumbnail images and all that stuff.
缩略图和其他一些内容。
But really, the main thing about
但实际上， GPX waypoint 最重要的
GPX waypoint is just the latitude and longitude.
属性还是经度值和纬度值。
So now we've made this new class, EditableWaypoint, which
所以我们写了一个新类， EditableWaypoint ，
is a GPX waypoint, but it has a settable coordinate, okay.
在原本的基础上，增加了可以设置的坐标。
So down here, instead of creating a GPX waypoint,
然后在这里，当我们长按的时候，我们将创建一个 EditableWaypoint ，
when we long press we're gonna create an editable waypoint,
替换掉原来创建GPX waypoint的方法，
okay.
好了。
One other thing you need to do though,
另外还有一件你需要做的事情就是
is that pin annotation, okay, the little
“钉”住一个小的标志，
pin, we need to say that it's draggable, so I'm gonna say
我们需要设置小标志的视图是可以拖动的，我们通过设置 view.draggable 就可以
view.draggable to set this thing to be draggable.
让它能够拖动了。
But I'm only going to do that if the annotation
但只有当它是一个 EditableWaypoint 时，
is an editable way point.
我才会把它设置为可拖动的。
Okay, remember is is kind of like as, but
好的，记住这一点，我们后面需要测试
you're just testing it to see if it is,
到底是不是这样的。
rather than casting it to be something else, okay.
还是其他什么情况。
So that's it.
好了，就这样。
So, let's go back.
然后让我们回来看下效果。
Now our user waypoints should be draggable.
现在我们的用户加的 waypoints 应该是可以拖动的了。
All right, we'll drop one here.
好的，我在这里有一个“钉”住的 。
And I can pick it up here and move it over onto the other
我再选中它，将它挪到这条河的另外一边，
side of the river there, okay, anywhere I want.
或是任意的什么地方。
Notice that these ones down here are not draggable.
注意啊，其他的这些都是不可以拖动的。
Can't drag them because they're not of class
不能拖动的原因就是因为它们不是 EditableWaypoint 类的对象
EditableWaypoint, they're just GPX.waypoint, okay?
它们只是 GPX.waypoint ，对吧？
So draggable is really easy to do.
所以拖动实现起来很容易。
So now I freed up that right detail disclosure call-out,
现在，我们接着处理展示右侧详细内容的，
and we're going to turn that into our edit uneditable
我准备把它加在我们这个 editable Waypoint上，
waypoint, right?
对吧？
Change the name field, change the info field,
需要修改名称的文本框，信息的文本框，
add an image to it, all that stuff.
然后加上一张图片，就这些了。
That's what we're gonna make that be.
这就是我们需要做的了。
So let's go back down here.
所以我们回来继续。
Here's the old code we had for
这时我们之前为 rightCalloutAccessoryView
that rightCalloutAccessoryView, and
写的代码，这里的大部分代码
I want most of that.
都是需要的。
But instead of adding that little detailed disclosure
原来这个当 waypoint 上有图片时，我们就会增加一个
when the waypoint has an image,
查看详细的小按钮。
I'm gonna do it whenever the annotation is an editable one.
现在我们要改成，如果这是一个可以编辑的航点的注释，就放置这个小按钮。
So if it's editable,
也就是，如果它是可以编辑的，
I'm gonna put that little detail disclosure there, okay.
我就在这里放一个查看详细的按钮。
So now, we have to modally segue because this new MVC,
好，我们对这个新的MVC必须使用模态的 Segue，
we're gonna need a new MVC that lets us edit the name and
这个新的MVC可以让用户为这个 waypoint
the image of a waypoint.
编辑名称和图片。
We're going to do that modally.
我们将用模态的方法。
We're gonna do a modal segue.
我们需要通过 modal segue 。
We just learned about modal segues.
刚刚学过的 modal segue 。
How are we gonna do that?
我们该怎么做呢？
Well this is the rightCalloutAccessoryView
这是 rightCalloutAccessoryView ，
here, so I'm gonna go down to where the CalloutAccessoryView
当 CalloutAccessoryView 被点击了，
is tapped, and right now it just always does the show
就会展示一个图片，
image segue way, which I still want it to do if we tapped on
我希望是能点击它，然后出现
the leftCalloutAccessoryView,
leftCalloutAccessoryView ，
but if we tapped on the right one, I want it to edit it.
如果我点击右边的，就可以直接编辑。
So I'm gonna put a little if-then in here to
所以你这里我就需要写一个 if－then 来达到
that effect.
这个效果。
So I'm actually gonna say, if the control that we tapped on.
这里我就是要写，如果我点击了
As a button which they both should be buttons okay, but
这个按钮，实际它们都应该是按钮，这里我只是
I'm just gonna make sure here.
我需要确认一下。
If the button type equals UI button type detail
接着判断 这个按钮的类型是不是  Detail Disclosures ，
disclosures, so if it's the detail disclosure button, then
如果这是一个 Detail Disclosure button，
I'm going to do my modal segue to edit my waypoint, okay.
我就使用我的 modal Segue 到编辑我的 waypoint ，
Otherwise, I'm going to do a little more of a check here.
否则，我就在这里做一个检查。
I'm going to say, if the waypoint equals the views
意思就是，如果这个 waypoint 的视图
annotation as a GPX.Waypoint,
对象的类型是 GPX.Waypoint ，
which it should because the only kind of.
现在是现在我们
An annotation that I even have,
只有一种类型，
aur GPX Waypoint annotations.
GPX Waypoint annotations 。
But in the future, what if I added something else in there?
但如果在后面，我们增加一些新的类型会怎么样呢？
So I'm just being a little careful.
所以我这里要小心点，多做点事情。
I'm also gonna say, if the Waypoint.imageURL does
我会说，如果 Waypoint.imageURL 不等于 nil ，
not equal nil, cuz if there's no URL in the Waypoint,
也就是是这里 waypoint 没有 URL 这个属性，
then I don't want to segue to that image showing
我就不会把图片展示到
the image view controller, right?
image view controller 上，对吧？
So, I'm just protecting myself a little bit here to make sure
这样我是为了保护我的程序，
that I actually have it.
确认它确实有这个属性。
Cuz I might have a thumbnail but
因为我可能有一个缩略图，
I don't have the image, possibly, unlikely.
但我并没有图片，这是有可能的。
All right. So, how about edit waypoint?
好了，那如果是 edit waypoint 该怎么样呢？
What are we going to do in edit waypoint?
我们后面该怎么做呢？
Well, we're just going to segue.
我需要调用 segue 。
So I'm going to perform a segue with identifier.
我们将会写 performSsegueWithIdentifier。
I need a new identifier because I'm not segueing to
我需要一个给这个 segue 设定新的名字，因为原来是“跳转”到
the image thing, I'm segueing to an editing waypoint thing.
一张图片 ，现在是跳转到一个可以编辑 waypoint 的视图。
So I have a constant for that,
我这里设置一个常量，
actually, called EditWaypointSegue.
叫做 EditWaypointSegue 。
Okay.
好的
So EditWaypointSegue is down in my constants sections here.
现在 EditWaypointSegue 就写在了我们的常量里面了，
It's Edit Waypoint.
就是 Edit Waypoint 。
Okay, so this is what we're going to have to make sure
好的，这就是保证我们调用的 segue 是我们在storyboad
we put in our storyboard for that segue.
里面增加的那个。
Just like we put this in our storyboard for
这个就像我们之前在 storyboard 里增加的
the image segue.
image segue 一样。
All right.
好的。
So it's at a waypoint.
这就是在 waypoint 要做的事情。
And sender, again, we'll have the sender be the view.
接着，sender，我们需要把这个 send 转换为 视图（view）。
Okay, the annotation view.
对的，应该是一个注释的视图（annotation view）。
Cuz that's really who's kind of causing this to happen,
这就是我们想要的效果，
cuz we're in its call out so it's the calling it out.
我们“叫“它出来，它就出来。
Now the other thing I'm going to do here is I'm
接下来我们要做的事情就是
actually going to deselect this annotation.
当我们不取消选中时，
Probably I would want to unwind,
我们需要“返回”到前一个页面
come back and reselect it.
并移除它。
But I want it to be deselected because it's currently showing
并且我希望它变成不非选中状态，因为我想换掉
the current state of the annotation,
当前正在展示详细信息的
of the waypoint, and I'm going to be changing that.
这个waypoint，对，我想换一个waypoint看看。
So when I come back, I don't want it to be there.
所以当我返回时，我希望是这样的。
Okay, it's showing the old data I wanted to be,
嗯，它把之前的数据展示给我了，
I either want you to have to force you to redisplay it or
我这里必须强制把内容给更新了，
maybe, if I were going to add more code,
为此，我们将多写一点代码。
I could make it so that it redisplayed.
来让它重新展示一次数据。
But, in any case, I definitely want this annotation to be
但其实，我真是希望当我要编辑这个注释点时候，它其实是
deselected when I segue it to go edit it.
非选中状态的。
Okay?
可以理解？
All right, so that's it.
好了，就这样。
That's all we need to do here.
我们就需要在这里。
We just need to go to our storyboard now and
我们先需要去到 Stroyboard 然后创建一个新的MVC，
create that new MVC that edits this thing and add this segue.
来用来编辑这些内容，并且加上一个Segue。
So let's do that.
好，我们开始吧。
Let's go to our storyboard, and
先到我们的 Stroyboard ,
we're gonna be segueing from our map view again.
我们还是会从我们的 Map View 开始创建一个 Segue，
Inside one of the call-outs we're going to be segueing.
我们需要链接到被呼唤出的视图中的一个。
So just like we have this segue right here,
嗯，对，我们就是要连接到这里，
that came from this little thing.
连接到这个小东西上。
Our new one's gonna come from this little guy, too.
我们新的连接讲从这里个小东西开始。
So let's go ahead and get one.
好，让我们继续来做。
Let's go down here and add a new view controller.
我要再加一个  View Controller 。
So I'm creating a brand new view controller.
这里我是创建来一个新的空白的 View Controller 。
We'll pop it up here.
我把它先放到这里。
Okay? Move it out of
可以？然后把它往外
the way a little.
稍微挪一下。
And I'm gonna segue,
接着我就开始创建 Segue ，
just the way I did before, from this thing.
可以之前做的一样，从这个小东西开始，
Control drag.
按住 Ctrl ，然后拖动，
Okay, to segue to this.
好了，连接到这里。
But this time I'm going to do present modally.
但这次我们希望是以模态的方式。
Last time we did show, we were in a navigation controller
上次因为我们是在  Navigation Controller 里面，
down there, but we said show.
所以我们可以直接设置为 show 。
So this time even though I'm in navigation controller,
而这次尽管我们也是在 Navigation Controller 里面，
I'm still going to say present modally,
我们也还是会设置为模态展示，
which is going to cause this new view controller to come up
这样我们就可以让新的 View Controller 出现时
over the whole screen.
占据整个屏幕。
Question? >> If you worked in
有问题吗？ >>  你现在是
a navigation controller letter and if not,
Naviation Controller 里面，那如果不是的话，
which one would you suggest using?
我该怎么做呢？
>> Yeah, so the question was,
>> 好的，这个问题是，
if I wasn't in a navigation controller.
如果我不是在 Navgation Controller ，
If you look here.
如果是在这里，
See this guy right here?
看到这个位置了？
He's in this navigation controller right here.
它是在 Navigation Controller 的旁边。
If I weren't in a navigation controller, would it make any
如果我现在不是在 Naviation Controller 里的话，我设置一个
difference to this modal segue and the answer is no.
modal segue 有什么区别吗？答案是没有区别。
Modal segues don't care where you are.
Modal segue 不会管你在哪里。
They're going to take over the screen and show themselves.
它们只是在直接在当前的屏幕上把内容展示出来，仅此而已。
Okay.
好了。
And the question of is it better to be or not to be,
这个问题就是做好呢，还是不做好呢？
if you're presenting modal it really doesn't matter.
如果你用模态的方式，不是非常必须的。
But if you're in a navigation controller it's nice because
如果你还时在 Navigation Controller 里，那就还好，因为你还有
you can have this kind of segue which is pushing, okay.
一个 Push 的 segue 可以使用。
And you could argue this whole editing of the waypoint,
你这里可能也会有疑惑，我们编辑 waypoint 的地方
maybe that should be a push.
也应该是使用 Push 的呀。
And you go push to a place where you edit it, and then
以 Push 形式的方式展示需要编辑的视图，
you hit save or done, but it's kind of ambiguous then unless.
然后可以点击保存，但这里有一点可能是不明确的。
When you edit it, you're going to change it live,
当你想想要编辑它时，你就先需要把它激活，
like we're going to do our modal one.
就像我们将要处理我们的模型（modal）。
So, I'm showing you this to show you modal segues, but
这里，我们是为来给你展示 Modal segue ，但实际上
I actually, if I were really writing an app,
如果是我自己写APP，
I'd probably push to this and
我会选择用 Push 的方式
have it be live editing, where if I change something,
并且保持它可以实时编辑，当我修改了什么地方，
it's changing that thing in real time.
这里的内容也跟着实时进行改动。
Cuz that's how I'm going to do this modal anyway.
这里我要执行处理这个模态对话框的话，
The modals, actually, may be better when you are presenting
实际上，当你展示完成之后，再允许它们变成可编辑的，
something that you're going to allow them to edit, and
这样会更好，然后再处理
then hit cancel, 'kay?
点击取消，
Versus Save.
和保存。
That modal might be better for that, but
这样处理会更好点，
here I'm just trying to show you the mechanics of modal.
但现在我将给你们展示的是 模态的机制。
So here's out modal segue right here.
这里是一个 modal segue ，
We gotta make sure we put its identifier,
我先给它取一个名字，
Edit Waypoint, we're gonna call it.
叫Edit Waypoint，我们就这么叫它。
You can see that segue 写的是 modal.
你可以看到这个 Segue 的类型是 modal。
And I told you here that you can control things like
我也和你们说过，你可以修改一些信息，比如展示类型
the presentation style of it.
presentation style 等等
And I'm going to show you that when we
等下我还会给你们展示如果是在iPad 上的话，
go look at this on an iPad in a moment here.
会是什么样子。
But for an iPhone it doesn't really matter because it's
但在iPhone上没有什么变化，出现方式
always going to slide up from the bottom.
一直都是从底部滑上来的。
That's the way iPhones present modal segues by default.
这个就是 iPhone 的 Modal segues 的默认（展示方式）。
Okay, so we have this nice thing, so let's go ahead and
好了，我们已经做完了，让我们运行一下
run this and see what this.
看看效果如何。
What we made happen here.
运行的效果将会是什么样的。
All right, so now I'm going to add a new thing here.
哦好的，我还要加一个东西呢。
It's dragable, right?
它应该是可以被拖动的，对吧？
I can pick it up, put it somewhere else.
我可以选中它，然后把它拖到其他的地方去。
It's here. It says dropped.
就是这这里，叫做 dropped 。
And now, when I click on this, notice that these guys,
现在，当我点击这，注意一些内容，
by the way, don't have the editable thing.
它们是不能被编辑的。
They still have their image, okay?
它们还是用的自己的图片，对吧？
But they don't have, they're editable.
但这些不是多，它们是可以被编辑的。
But this one has this whole editable, so
这个事可以被编辑的，所以
I'm going to click on this and we'll see what happens.
我点击一下，看看会发生什么。
Okay?
对吧？
Perfect. Slides up from the bottom.
完美，从底部滑上来的。
I'm this modal MVC where I can edit the waypoint.
我现在是在模态的MVC里，我可以直接 waypoint 。
Now we have a built-in UI to do that, but, here we are.
现在我有内置的 UI 做这些工作，就是它们。
Kay?
对吧？
So, now we're going to put our UI in here to edit this.
所以我们现在就要在这里放一些控件作为可以编辑的，
So let's do that.
让我们开始吧。
That's right here.
就在这里。
It's going to be a pretty simple UI,
这是一个非常简单的 UI 。
I'm just going to get a couple of text fields out here.
我只需要放一些 Text Field （文本框）就好了。
Okay, a text field for the name, a text field for
一个保存名称的文本框，
that little info field.
一个保存信息的文本框
A label for each of those.
然后在前面都为他们加上一个 Label 。
That's pretty much my entire UI.
这就是我们要的 UI 了。
One label is called Name.
一个 Label 叫做 Name 。
I'm gonna add those, it will be my line.
它们应该排在同一行。
The other one is called, let's call it Info.
另一个我们就叫做 Info 。
Have that be right aligned.
让它们都对齐好。
We'll put this up in the corner here and
我们可以点击这个地方，会自动为我们加上
do all of our auto-layout constraints.
auto-layout 的限制值。
We'll put that there,
我们这样来放，
we'll put this one up in this corner.
我将把其中一个放在这个角。
Actually we'll have them align their baselines right there,
实际上我们是让它们都和这 baselines 刚好对齐，
it's a good idea.
这是一个好办法。
This guy.
这些，
Try and align.
也一样对齐。
Whoops.
哦。
Align his baseline if we can.
也和它的 baseline 对齐。
Yeah, there he is.
对，就是这样。
Yeah, there we go.
好的，我们继续。
There and align the baseline.
这里有一条可以对齐的 baseline。
Let's drag this all the way over here like this.
让我们把其他的内容也拖拽成这样。
This one over here, we'll try to line these up.
我会让它们可以排成一行。
Okay, one thing that I want to do here is.
好的，我想这个是这样的。
So let's just set all our constraints here at all once.
然后让我们一次性的生成我们的限制值（constraints）吧。
I'm going to do it really quickly.
我下面会很快的把这些做好。
Again, you've seen so
你们已经看多了很多关于
many how to layout demos you don't see a little more,
布局的例子，但你们没有看到过，这次
but I'm going to left this guy to the trailing edge.
我让这个东西和下面的边缘“联系”起来。
I'm going to hook this guy to the trailing edge.
我将把它们进行“关联”。
I'm gonna hook this guy to the top.
然后我会把这个东西和顶部进行“关联”。
I'm gonna hook this guy to the bottom, but
我将把这个东西到关联到底部，
this is kind of an interesting one because I'm going to hook
但有意思的地方是，这个关联后的值是
him to the bottom with greater than or equal.
大于或等于。
Because I really just want to make sure that he's
因为我只是想让这个距离的值是从这个值
the standard value distance away from the bottom or
到底部边缘或是更多一点
more, okay.
都可以。
I don't really care,
我并不太在意这个，
I just never want him to smash into the bottom.
我只是希望它能够和底部边缘有一定的距离。
So we'll do that.
所以我才这么做。
Let's go ahead and put this one here.
让我们继续，来处理这个
Leading space.
Leading space。
This one also, leading.
这个头部的。
Let's put these two separated by a vertical space.
我们先在垂直距离方向放上两个间隔。
Let's separate these.
让我们把他们间隔开。
Let's separate this.
然后把这个也分开。
I want this one and this one, sorry, this one and this one,
我想把这个和这个，哦，不对，是这个和这个，
to always be lined up their left edges.
一直和他们的左边缘靠齐。
Right, I don't want this to be ragged edged,
对的，我不想他们和边缘的距离参差不齐的，
so I'm gonna line their left edges up as well.
所以我想也让他们在左侧边缘进行对齐。
So it looks like we got all of our things except for
这样看起来我们把事情搞定了，处理
vertical position for name.
这个名字的垂直位置。
Okay, that's because,
对对，这是因为，
let's line up these baselines, baseline here, baseline here.
我们把他们根据这些 baseline 排成一行后，选择 baseline here ， baseline here 。
All right, so all gone, everything's lined up, okay.
好的，所有的内容都排版好了。
Wow we didn't even need to update our frames,
我现在只需要更新一下展示就好了，
we have this perfect looking UI here, okay.
我们这个 UI 看起来真是不错呀。
Sound good?
是不错吧？
All right, now let's wire these text fields up.
好的，然后让我们把这些文本框和代码“链接”起来吧。
So to wire these text field up,
好，我们现在就开始“链接”。
we need a custom subclass of UIViewController.
我们先是需要一个 UIViewController 的子类。
Right, cuz now this is just a generic,
好的，因为现在它还是一个可以通用的，
if we look at its identity inspector,
如果我们在 Inspector 的 Identity 栏目来中看，
it's a generic UIViewController, so
它还是一个通用的 UIViewController，
we need a custom subclass, no problem.
所以我们需要自己定义一个子类，
We'll do that, we know how to do that.
这个我们是知道怎么做的。
Okay, we're gonna call this our
好的，我们就叫它
EditWaypointViewController, cuz that's what it does.
EditWaypointViewController ，因为它的功能就是这个
This MVC that we're putting up, it edits waypoints so
我们现在做的这个 MVC 就是用来编辑 waypoint ，
we'll call it EditWaypointViewController.
我们就叫它 EditWaypointViewController 。
Here it is.
这样就好了。
Let's go back to our storyboard here.
然后我们回到我们的 storyboard 。
I'm gonna change this guy's identity to be
我们把它对应的 Identity 改为
EditWaypointViewController, okay.
EditWaypointViewController，没问题吧。
So it's on automatic mode here so, we got our thing here.
这里我们得到了一些自动生成的代码。
I'm going to delete all but viewDidLoad, okay.
我只留下 viewDidLoad ，其他的都删掉。
Let's go and hook these two things up, these text fields.
然后让我们把按钮和代码直接“关联”起来。
So, I'm gonna Control-Drag here,
我将按住 Ctrl 然后拖到这里，
we'll call this the nameTextField.
我们就叫它 nameTextField 。
And we'll drag this one, we'll call it the infoTextField,
我们还会把这个也拖过来，我们就叫它 infoTextField 。
okay, so there is our UI.
好的，这就是我们的 UI 。
Now, we need to think a little bit at what's the model for
现在，我们要想一下我们 EditWaypointViewController 的对应的
our EditWaypointViewController.
模型（Model）的情况。
Can anyone think of what the model for
你们有谁能可以想到这个用来编辑 waypoint 的 MVC
an MVC that edits a waypoint, what would be its model?
对应的模型应该是什么？
What does it do?
它是用来做什么的呢？
Edits a waypoint, right?
编辑 waypoint ，对吧？
So its model might be a waypoint?
所以这个模型就应该是一个 waypoint ，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
Let's make it be the waypoint to edit, okay?
我们现在就做一个可以编辑的 waypoint。
So it's going to be an editable waypoint.
它就将作为一个可以编辑的 waypoint。
It's gonna be the model for this viewController.
也就是这个视图控制器的模型。
Anytime you're trying to determine, hm,
在任何时候你想确定你的
what's my model?
模型是什么？
You always want to think,
你可以这样想，
what does this thing do, what does it operate on?
（这个视图控制器）是做什么的，它要操作什么？
That's usually gonna be its model.
那么它通常就是模型。
Okay, either how it functions or what it operates on,
对的，如果去对它进行操作或处理的，
that's usually gonna be the model, all right.
那么这个就是模型。
So this thing edits a waypoint, so
我们现在就是要编辑一个 waypoint，
that's going to be its model.
所以它就是模型。
So now, let's get some more space here.
现在，我们先把调整一下窗口的位置。
Let's keep our view and model in sync, okay.
同时可以看到我们的视图和我们模型，好的。
One of the first things we want to do actually when we
我们首先想要做的是，当我们把模型放到视图里面，希望
put a model in or add view is keep them in sync, so
保持两者的同步，也就是说
that they're always reflecting each other.
他们之间的事保持相互“联系”的。
So let's do that by having here, a div set
所以我们在这里这么来做，
on the model that calls some update UI thing, okay.
在模型上调用更新 UI 的方法。
And we'll do the exact same thing down here, as well.
我们将在这里也做同样的事情。
So if you set either text field,
所以如果你在text field里修改了内容，
we're going to update the model.
我们也将会更新模型。
What did I do wrong here, oh I don't have updateUI.
我们做错了什么吗？我没有 updateUI 这个方法。
Okay, so let's go ahead and, func updateUI.
好的，让我们先来写 func updateUI 。
So we've got an updateUI, what do we need to do in updateUI?
好，现在我们有了 updateUI 这个方法了，那我们这个方法要做些什么呢？
Really, we just need to update our text fields from our
实际上，我们只是需要把我们的waypoint的值更新到
waypoints.
textfield 上就可以了。
So I'm gonna say, nameTextField.text
所以就应该是， nameTextField.txt
= waypointToEdit.name, and
= waypointToEdit.name ，和
the infoTextField.text = waypointToEdit.info.
infoTextField.text = waypointToEdit.info。
Okay, so that's it.
好来，就这样。
Let's also update our UI in viewDidLoad, that way,
然后我们在 viewDidLoad 这个方法里也调用一次 updateUI 这个方法。
if our model got set before our outlets were loaded,
以防止模型在我们的 UI 加载之后被更新过，
this will catch them up to speed, okay.
这样现在就能够保持两者同步了。
So it's a very common pattern, here, to updateUI
这是一个非常常用的“模式”，当你的模型发生变化的时候，更新你的UI
when your model changes and also update in viewDidLoad.
同时在 viewDidLoad 方法里也更新一次 UI。
Okay, because remember outlets are not set, unfortunately,
好的，有的时候当我们在为 segue 准备 MVC 的时候， outlets 可能
sometimes during prepare for segue, for example.
还没有被加载完成，这个会比较麻烦，我们来看下例子。
okay, so let's see what this looks like.
让我们看到到底会是什么样。
I'm actually gonna run this one on
因为我要为你展示一下这个特别的
the phone because I wanna show you
UI 问题，所以我会让程序运行在
a particular problem we have with this UI so far.
真实的设备上。
Okay, let me put this on the screen here.
好，让我们把这个放到屏幕上来看。
Okay, so here's our UI, I'm gonna just tap and
好，这是我们的 UI ，我来把它拖到
hold to drop here, okay, and now I'm gonna click on it.
这里，让我点击一下它。
I'm gonna press our new editing button and
我将要点击我们新的这个编辑按钮，然后就可以看到
here we have our UI.
我们的新的 UI 。
That's good our UI's appearing.
看，我们的 UI 展示出来了，很好！
A couple of problems here, one, no keyboard.
但这里也有不少问题，首先，没有键盘。
Okay, our UI has appeared here, but
是的，我们的 UI 展示在这里了，
if there's not keyboard that's not so good, but
但如果这里没有键盘不能输入，肯定是不可以的，
if I touch on a text field it appears.
但如果我一旦点击了 text field 之后，键盘就会出现了。
Okay, that's kind of good except for
好吧，而比较好的用户体验应该是
when my the thing first comes up I probably want it to
UI 展示的同时，就能看到
have a keyboard.
键盘。
So we're going to put in some code to become first responder
所以我们需要加一点代码，让我们的 text field 作为第一个响应者
on one of those text fields, okay.
（first responser）。
Right off the bat.
除了这个问题。
Another problem is,
另外一个问题是，
I can never make this keyboard go away, okay.
键盘没有办法消失。
No matter what I press, I press return, click on
无论我按什么，我按过 return 键，
[INAUDIBLE], and I can't make it go away, that's a problem.
我也不能让键盘消失，这是一个问题。
Now, I don't have anything down at the bottom right now,
现在我在右下角没有任何东西。
but when we start having an image in our waypoint editor,
但当我们在 waypoint 的编辑（器）里增加了一张图片的话，
then it's gonna cover up that image.
这里也将现实这张图片。
We need a way for
我需要有一个解决方案，
the return key on the keyboard that I'm pressing down here,
当我点击 return 键之后，
to make these things  first responder, okay.
可以放弃第一响应者（first responder）。
Let's fix those things really quickly, they're easy to fix.
我们可以很快的把这些问题解决掉，解决它们很容易。
Become first responder, we can just do in viewDidLoad.
成为第一响应者（first responder），我们需要在 viewDidLoad 方法里，
I'm just gonna say, name text field become first responder,
我只需要写上 nameTextField.becomeFirst responder 就可以了
so as soon as this thing is created it's gonna immediately
也就是说当这个内容刚刚被创建出来，就把 text field 作为
make that text field be the first responder, okay?
第一响应者 （first responder）。
So that's easy.
很容易的。
Making the return key resign first responder requires us
然后让点击 return 键 可以取消当前的第一响应者 （first responder）的话，
to, if you remember from last time, become UI text field
你们是否还记得上一次，增加 UITextField 的 delegates 然后实现了
delegates, and implement this method, text field should
其中这个方法 textFieldShouldEndEditingOrShouldEndReturn。
end editing or should end return, here it is, okay.
对，就是它。
So here,
在这里，
when a text field hits the return key, I'm going to say
当一个 text field “监测”到点击了 return 键，我就会写
textField.resignFirstResponder.
textField.resignFirstResponder。
And then we'll let it do whatever it normally does.
这就是我们通常情况下的做法。
Okay, so that solves both of those problems.
好了，这样就把两个问题都解决了。
Oh, whoops, one quick thing we need to do before
好的，在我们“验证“之前，我们还有一件
we do that is,
事情需要做。
if we're gonna have this text field delegate method called,
如果调用了这个代理的方法
we need to obviously make, oh, I did this totally wrong.
我们需要显式的做。。。我做错了。
Sorry.
抱歉。
This should be, nobody caught me on this, but
这里应该是，没有回调用我，担
this should be on the model, okay.
它应该是发生在模型上。（模型需要调用的意思）
Add those on the text fields.
这些是在 text field。
All right, it's the model that wants
对的，应该是模型希望能够更新 UI，
to update the UI not the text fields, okay?
并不是 text field 要更新UI，对吧?
What the text fields want when they're didSet
在设置 textField的的时候，需要设置他的
is they want to set their delegates equal to self.
deletaget 等于  self 。
That's what they wanna do, okay.
这就是我们要做的。
Guys, pay attention.
大家，注意一下。
I count on you guys to catch me doing these things.
我希望你们看懂了我刚才做的。
Okay, everyone understand that?
好的，每个人都懂了吗？
The model setting that wants to update the UI, the text
是这个模型希望可以更新 UI ，这个textfield 只是
field, just want to set themselves as the delegate.
把他们设置为自己的代理（delegate）。
See, you let me do another thing here.
看，你让我做另外一件事的意思。
Okay, there we go.
好，那让我们继续。
So now both text fields have self as their delegate, so
现在两个 text field 都有了他们各自的代理，所以他们
they're both going to call ShouldReturn, okay.
可以调用 ShouldReturn...这个方法。
So let's try that.
让我们试试看那就。
Are we still up there, yes.
我们还是在这里，对对。
Okay. Again, here I'm gonna add one.
好，我们再增加一个。
Click here.
点击这里。
Let's bring up our new MVC.
然后我们到我们新的 MVC 。
Here it is.
就是这里。
Keyboard comes up, excellent.
键盘出现了，很好！
And if I hit Return, keyboard goes away.
如果我点击 return 键， 键盘消失了。
And if I go to Back, it comes back.
如果我点击返回，它就返回来。
So that's much more control.
这里需要更多的控制。
And if you're doing this in the simulator, it seems like,
如果你是在模拟器里运行，这个可能看起来
oh, this is all great.
完全没有问题。
But then when you run it on the device, you're like, oh,
但如果你是在真机上运行，你就会发现，
well that's not very useable, okay.
好像不是那么好用的。
So you've got to be careful to make sure things actually
这里你要特别注意，确保你的 App 可以在真机上
are useable on the device.
正确运行。
All right.
好的。
That's that, so now we've kind of set up our UI.
就是这样了，我们已经把我们的 UI 部分完成了。
But actually, there's one other problem with this.
不过实际上，这里还有另外一个问题。
Let's go ahead and take a look at this other problem we got.
让我们去看看下另外这个问题，
Which is when I add a thing here is I might type in
当我想增加一个内容的时候，我会输入它的名字，
the name, like I think I put that pin on the golf course
比如我想“钉”在这个地方点点叫做 “glof course”
there or something.
之类的。
Right?
可以吧？
Golf course, okay, snowed, whatever.
“Golf course”，好的，随便什么名字吧。
But now there's no way for me to get back.
但这里我却没办法回去了。
[LAUGH].
［笑］
You see?
看到了？
How can I get back?
我怎么才能回去？
I've changed the things I want, now I want to get back,
我已经把我需要修改的内容改好了，我想返回，
I want to dismiss this thing and
我想把当前的移除，然后
get back, so we need some user interface here to get back.
回到前一个界面，所以我们需要增加一个新的 UI 控件让我能够返回。
The other thing is, when we make changes in these text
另一个问题时，当我在text fields 里面修改了内容之后，
fields, it's not actually changing the waypoint, okay?
并没有在体现在 waypoint 上，对吧？
So we need you to fix both those things.
所以我们需要修改这两个问题。
So let's fix the changing in the way point.
让我们先修改这个编辑 waypoint 的这个问题。
Now, this one I'm gonna use notifications for.
这里，我会使用 Notification 来实现。
Because I want to show you a little bit more
因为我想给你们多展示一下 Notification 的用法。
about notifications that we really didn't cover
我们上次没有机会
when we did the notifications last time.
实际使用 Notification 。
So, text fields it turns out, they have a notification.
这里，当text fields 一出现，这里会一个 Notification 。
Okay, in fact they have a couple of notifications.
好吧，实际上它时有一组 Notification。
Three notifications, I think, even.
我记得可能是 三个 Notification
But one of them is ui text field,
其中有一个是
text did change notification.
UITextfieldTextDidChangeNotification 。
So you can sign up to hear from a text field whenever its
这样这个 textfield 里的值发生任何变化，你都可以监听。
text changes.
Now, that's gonna be really valuable for us, here.
现在有这个 Notification 对我们来说就很有用了。
Because whenever the text field's text changes,
因为任何时候 text field 里的值发生变化，
we can update our wave point.
我们就可以更新我们的 waypoint 的值
Right?
对吧？
So, how do we do that?
好，那我们该怎么做？
How do we make that work?
我们怎么来实现这个？
Well, turns out we want to put this in viewDidappear, so
嗯，这里我们会在 viewDidAppear 方法里来写，
in viewDidappear, okay, super.viewDidappear.
在 viewDidAppear ，对，先要调用 super.viewDidAppear 。
I'm just gonna call a method here,
让我在这里要调用一个方法，
called observeTextFields.
这个方法就叫做 observeTextfield  吧。
Okay?
可以？
In an ovserveTextfield, I am going to set myself up
在这个 ovserveTextfield 方法里，我将把我自己
to observe changes made in those text fields.
设置为“监听”这些 textField 的变化的代理对象。
All right?
对吧？
And, so I'm gonna do that with the notification center, so
所以我要通过 NotificationCenter ，得到center
I'm gonna get my center, which is NS Notification center.
类型是为  NSNotificationCenter
Default center.
Default center 。
I'm also going to specify the queue I want this on which is,
我还要指明在这个“通知”队列里我们需要的的是哪个，
of course, the main queue, so I'm gonna say, main queue.
这个“队列”就是指主队列。
And them I'm just gonna say, use that thing we had before,
接着我来写，我们之前也这么做过的，
Center Add Observer, for name which is this.
Center add Observer 参数的名字是
And the name of this notification is UI Text Field.
这个名字就是 UITextField 的 notification  的这个
TextDidChangeNotification.
TextDidChangeNotification 方法。
'Kay?
对吧？
So, so far, this notification is nothing new to you.
到现在为止，关于 Notification 还没有什么新的内容。
Object is the object I care about if it changes,
这个Object 就是我们需要的被改变内容的对象，
which is, let's say, the name text field, in this case.
也就是说，这里就应该是 nameTextField ，
'Kay?
对吧？
Queue is the queue, and the block, okay, I'm gonna do the.
在队列和 block，对的，就是这里
Our magic trick here of
我将会用一个有点神奇的方法
closing off the end of that, I'll get rid of that.
关掉这个，我可以来删掉掉这些。
And then put our block on the end here.
然后把我们的 block 放在这里的最后。
So here are the argument, I'll just call it notification.
这是参数，我直接调用 notification.
That's the notification that cames back, coming back.
这个notification的返回值。
And all I wanna do here is if I can let waypoint,
然后我这里就是让 let waypoint 等于
equal our waypointToEdit.
我们的 waypointToEdit 。
Okay, so we can get our waypoint.
这样我们就能得到我们的 waypoint 。
Then, I'm just going to set the waypoint's name
接着我们就只需要nameTextfield的值赋给
equal to the name text field's text.
waypoint的name就可以了。
So every time the name text field changes here,
所以每次name text field的值发生了变化，
I'm just going to update the name of our waypoint.
我都会更新我们的 waypoint 的名称属性。
And exactly the same for the info.
保持内容一直是同步的。
So all we have to change here is
接着我们也必须对这个info text fields
info text fields coming in here.
也进行相应的修改。
And this is going to be updated to info.
这里是要更新 info。
And this is the info.
这个是 info。
Now so far, so good.
到目前为止，都很好。
You're probably like oh, okay it makes sense.
你可能会想，嗯，这个很合理的。
You haven't taught us anything new about notification.
关于 notificaton 你已经没有什么可学的了。
But there's a very important piece of this
但这里有一个特别重要的地方，
puzzle right here.
容易出错的地方。
What happens when this MBC gets dismissed?
如果一旦 MBC 被移除了，会发生什么？
These observers are still trying to observe
这些观察者（observers）还在尝试监听
those text fields.
这些 text fields 。
Even those text fields could be have gone away,
甚至这些 text field 可能已经被移除了。
they won't because these closures are gonna keep
这是因为这些 text field 可能还被
those text fields in memory.
保存在内存中。
And also, self can never go away because
也是这样的，他们自己是永远无法把自己删除的，
these closures are gonna be keep self in memory.
因为这些“闭包”函数将会一直将它们保存在内存里。
So this is a problem, so when you add an observer like this
所以这是一个问题，所以当你在这样的情况下增加一个 观察器（observer）
and your MVCs ever going to go away,
同时你的 MVC 将会被移除掉，
which our last MVC never went away, it was the root MVC so
而我们最后的这个 MVC 却一直不会被移除，它是一个根视图控制器(MVC)
we added that observer for a name.
所以我们这个增加的 observer ，
We probably could just leave it there forever,
我们只能一直将它留在那里了，
because it's never going to go away.
因为它也是不会移除的。
Although good design,
尽管一个好的设计来看，
maybe even that one would know how to go away.
可能它自己是知道如何将自己移除的。
But how do we go away?
但该怎么做呢？
And the answer is that this returns a little cookie, okay?
方法就是，返回一小段 cookie ，对吧？
So it returns a cookie.
它是返回一段 cookie 的话。
I'm gonna make storage for these two cookies.
我将会讲这些 cookies 保存起来。
One I'm gonna call it the name text field observer, and
我讲会调用 nameTextfieldObserver ,
it's a type NSObjectProtocol.
这个对象的（协议）类型是 NSObject Protcol 。
So NSObjectProtocol just means it's something
这里 NSObjectProtocol 的意思是，这个对象在“过去”的
that used to be an NS object in the old world.
的世界里是被当作 NSObject 对象来看待的。
Okay, in the old, objective C world.
这个过去的意思是 ，Objective C 世界的意思。
That's all that means for an NS object protocol.
这些具体有关 NSObject Protocol 的具体内容，
We don't even know,
我们不了解，
we don't care what's in the NS object protocol for
这里我们也不需要懂，
the purposes of this, because really, this is just a cookie.
因为实际上，这就是一段 cookie 。
It's just something that it gives us that we can give back
这恰好就是我们当我们“沟通”的时候，
to it when we wanna talk about this thing.
所需要的内容。
So, here's this observer,
这个是 观察器 （oberver），
and I'm gonna say here ntfObserver equals that.
我这里让 ntfObserver 等于这个。
I'm gonna say itfObserver equals that.
然后让 itfObserver 等于它。
So I've added these observers and I got this cookie back.
我已经增加了这些 observer 同时我也可以获得它返回的 cookie 。
Now, when I'm done observing,
一旦当我完成了观察。
I need to remove this cookie from the notification center.
我就需要把这段 cookie 从 notificaton cenert 中删除。
So I'm gonna do that in view will disappear.
我将在 viewWillDisappear 这个方法里来做这件事。
Okay, so, when my view will disappear, okay?
是的，当我们的视图将要消失的时候，对吧？
I don't need to look at those text fields anymore after I've
我已经不需要在“监控”这些text field了，因为它们马上就不会出现在
gone off screen.
屏幕上了。
They can't be changing because I'm not even on screen
就是因为我在屏幕上都不会看到它们了，所以它们肯定也不会被
right now.
修改了。
I'm just gonna say
我只要这些来写，
NSNotificationCenter.defaultCenter.
NSNotificationCenter.defaultCenter
Actually, let's check and make sure they're not nil because
这里我们还是要检查下它们是不是nil ，因为这里我设置的这些字段内容
see I made these fields optional, so we'll say if.
是 optional 的，所以我要写 if
Observer if let, let observer equal
Observer if let ，let observer 等于
the mean text field observer, than notification center.
这个 text fileld observer ，然后在notification center
Remove that observer.
中删除这个 observer。
So you can see how I've never had to actually look inside
这里你可以看到，我根本没有去看内部发生了什么，或是里面是什么内容，
and see what this thing is, I don't send it any messages,
我也没有发送任何消息，
I just get the cookie here and then I pass it along in here.
我只是得到 cookie 然后直接传递到这里。
Except for this is observer, because I've lighted it.
除了它是 observer，因为我已经专门“处理”过它。
Okay, so that's all we had to do.
好了，这就是全部我们需要做的。
Same thing here.
同样的思路。
We'll do the same thing with the other cookie.
我们也需要对其他的cookie也做同样的处理。
This is the ITF observer, info text field.
这是 ITFObserber ，针对 info text field 。
So this pattern by the way, of starting to observe something
顺便说下这种模式，启动一个 observer 都是在 viewDidAppear 方法里调用，
in view did appear, and then stopping observing from it in
然后停止 观察（observer）都是在 viewWillDisappear
view will disappear is a very common way to do this.
方法里处理，这是一个比较通用的处理方式。
Okay, because usually, any notifications like keyboard
这是因为，通常，任何一个 notification ，比如 键盘的修改，
will change, or something like that, there's keyboard will
或是其他类似的，这里有一个 keyboardwillAppear 的，
appear, you don't care about that if you're not on screen.
你是不需要考虑他们是不是已经出现在屏幕上。
So there's a perfect place to add and remove this.
所以这是一个非常好的位置用来增加或删除。
Does everyone understand what's going on here?
是不是每个人都明白了发生了什么事情吧？
You add to these notifications so
你增加了这些 notifications ，所以任何时候
every time it checks changes,
它有修改的话，
it's gonna update our way point, but
都会直接更新我们的 waypoint，
we don't wanna be doing that when we're not on screen.
但我们不希望当我们的内容已经不在屏幕上，它们还继续监控。
And we don't wanna have these closures,
我们不需要这些"闭包"程序,
this closure right here, and this closure right here.
这个“闭包”这里，就是这里。
We don't want them keeping self, and this text field
我们不希望他们继续持有当前对象，
through self, we don't want them keeping them in heap.
我们不希望在堆上还继续保存着它们。
When we, when our MVC goes away,
当我们的 MVC 消失了之后，
we want it to go completely away, out of the heap.
我们希望是全部消失，完全从堆上移除。
All right. So that's notification.
好的，那就是 notification。
That's your little DL notification code.
那是有关 notification 的一段代码。
Now let's fix that other problem,
好，下面让我们来改另外一个问题。
the problem where there's no way to dismiss the thing.
这个问题是我们没有办法移除内容。
It comes up and we can't dismiss it.
它出现之后，我们没办法移除掉它。
And there's a number of ways we could do that.
事实上这里有好几个方法可以解决这个问题。
We could put a little Done button down in the middle
我们可以在界面中间放一个
somewhere of that UI.
Done 按钮。
But actually, I'm going to do it by putting this
但这次，我是会把我们的UI 放到 Navigation Controller 里。
user interface in an navigation controller.
Now, why am I gonna put it in navigation controller?
那我为什么要这么做呢？
Two reasons.
两个理由。
One, users are used to the look of navigation controllers
一、在 Navigation Controller 控制器下，用户可以在顶部看到一个
being the title bars and maybe there are buttons up there, so
标题条，然后旁边的位置特别适合放一个
it's a good place to put a Done button.
Done 的按钮。
Also, it gives me a title, okay?
同时我还可以设置一个标题，对吧？
When this thing came up and
当它一出现，只是一个空白的屏幕
it was just a blank screen with these two fields,
上有两个文本框，
it's a little disconcerting.
看起来有点“囧”呀。
What's happening?
会怎么样呢？
Whereas, if I have a title on top, like, Edit Waypoint,
这里，如果有一个标题在顶部，比如 Edit Waypoint
it'll be clear what the heck is going on.
将会明确很多。
So I'm just gonna select this, right here, and
所以我会选择这个方案，点击这里的
do Embed In Navigation Controller.
Embed In Navigation Controller
'Kay? So
对吧
it puts a Navigation Controller.
这里我们放入了一个 Navigation Controller。
Now, I can, for example, put a title, Edit Waypoint, in here.
现在，举个例子来说，可以加一个标题， Edit Waypoint ，在这里。
And, also, I can have a Done button here.
然后我还可以增加一个 Done 按钮。
So let's go ahead and put a Done button in there.
好，那我们现在就在这里加一个 Done 按钮。
Down here to Bar Button Item.
往下找， 叫 Bar Button Item 。
Here's a Bar Button Item.
就这这里了， Bar Button Item 。
We'll put it right here.
我们把它拖到这里。
We'll call it Done.
给它命名为 Done 。
And then let's go ahead and wire that Done button up.
然后让我们继续把这个按钮和代码连接在一起。
Okay. We'll wire it
好的，我想我们还是把它
up at the top here, I guess.
链接到代码的最上面这里。
Just Ctrl+drag from this right in here.
就是按住 Ctrl 然后拖到这里就好。
And, so when we hit Done, all we're going to do is dismiss.
现在我们需要能做到当我们点击了 Done ， 我们就能把它移除了。
So this is just going to be an action,
所以这个是需要一个 Action 。
bar button item action, we'll call it done.
bar button item action ，我们就给它命名为 done 。
And, inside this Done, right here.
然后在这个方法里，就是这里。
Sorry, we're going to go back to wide.
不好意思，我们要先把屏幕弄宽点。
Okay?
可以？
Inside this done action when the done button is pressed,
当 done 按钮被按下的时候，我们只需要在 done
I'm just going to say presenting
这个action 方法里，只需要写
view controller.dismiss.
viewController.dismiss 。
Okay? So, dismiss,
懂了？所以，直接移除，
I'm asking the presenting view controller who presented me,
我们问当前展示的的视图控制器，谁展示的我。
please dismiss whoever you just presented.
然后移除掉当前正在展示的。
And, in fact, if my presenting view controller has presented
然后，实际上，如果展示我的视图控制器已经展示了我之后，
me and I've presented someone else, when I do this dismiss,
然后我又展示里其他的，当我移除了之后，
it's going to dismiss all of us.
就会将所有内容都移除掉。
Okay?
懂了？
So, yes, we do want to animate it and, no,
是的，这里我还是需要一个动画效果，
we don't want to find out when the dismiss happens, okay?
当移除了之后，我们就不想看到它了，对吧？
Okay. So that's it.
好，就是这样了。
So that done button will allow us to dismiss.
这里这个 done 按钮就是能够实现移除。
All right. So, let's take a look,
好的，这样让我们来看下。
see if we fixed those two problems.
看下这两个问题是否被修复了。
And we only have one more piece to go to wire this up
我们在这之后已经有了一小部分。
after this.
All right.
好的。
So, we're going to add, along with the long press,
好，我们先长按，然后增加一个。
I'm gonna click, I'm gonna edit it.
我会先点击，然后编辑一下。
Here it is.
在这里。
Notice now I have this nice title, Edit Waypoint.
就可以看到，我们已经一个标题， Edit Waypoint 。
I can set this to be again, golf or something.
我可以重新设置这些内容，golf 或是其他什么内容。
I'm not gonna type too much because it's not gonna work
这里我们准备多输入些，因为这样程序是会有问题无法正确进行的，
and you're going to see why in a moment.
你们马上就会看到了。
But here it is.
但现在在这里，
Okay. We have this, we can return.
好的，我们已经了这个，我们可以返回了。
This is great.
这个太好了。
Our NBC's exactly what we want.
我们的 NBC 很好帮我们实现了我们想要的。
Now, I'm gonna hit Done.
现在，我点击 Done 按钮。
It dismisses it.
它已经被移除（消失）了。
Now, let's look and oh, it still says Dropped.
现在，让我们再看下，它始终还是被选装的状态。
Okay? Why is that?
嗯？为什么会这样？
That's because we didn't prepare that segue.
这是因为我们没有为这个 segue 准备好。
Okay?
对吧？
And modal segue is like any other segue,
modal seggue 和其他的 segue 一样的，
if you don't prepare it,
如果你不预先做设置的话，
it's going to not going to know what it's working on.
它就不知道它该如何工作。
So we need to set each modal, which is the waypoint to edit
所以我们需要为这个编辑 waypoint 的模态对话看进行
and we do that in prepare for segue.
准备和设置。
We already have a prepare for
我们之前已经对 GPXViewConrtoller 的 segue
segue in our GPX view controller right here.
进行了提前的准备和设置。
Prepares for the image viewing 1, so
包括对于图片的浏览的准备，这里
we just need to put another else if the segue's
我们是需要另外一个 else if ，来根据segue 的标识符
identifier equals our new EditWaypointSegue.
进行判断，看是不是我们的 EditWaypointSegue 。
Okay?
对吧？
And in here, what do we need to do?
在这里，我们该怎么做呢？
Again, just like any other one, we need to get the thing
是的，就是想另外的一个，我们需要对当前我指的这个
we're pointing to, that we're segueing to and set it up.
我们需要跳转过去，然后做设置。
So we're going to say if the, I'll go, what did I call it,
所以这里我将会这么写，我想下该叫它什么呢，
EWVC, okay, EditWaypointViewController.
EWVC ，对的，EditWaypointViewController。
If we can let the EditWaypointViewController
如果我们能让 EditWaypointViewController
equal the segue's destination as and
等于 segue 的跳转过去的目标是
EditWaypointViewController.
EditWaypointViewController。
Okay, then now we've got this Edit Way View Controller.
这样，我们就能得到这个 EditWaypointViewController ，
We can set the EditWaypointViewControllers,
我就可以设置 EditWaypointViewController 的 wayPoint 属性
way point to edit equal to a way point.
等于当前的 waypoint 。
So, we need to get our waypoint,
这里我们需要得到我们的 waypoint ，
which I'm actually gonna steal from right here,
就是我们想从这里传递过去的那个 waypoint ，
because we already have a nice line of code that does that.
因为我们已经写过一行很不错的代码，可以做到这个。
Okay.
好的。
So there's our waypoint.
现在已经有了我们的航点（waypoint）。
Now this, oh, sorry, this also.
不是这个，哦，抱歉，是这个。
Notice this is complaining.
注意这里已经报错了。
See, this says error.
看，这里报错的。
I'm trying to set the waypoint to edit to waypoint and
我试着把这个waypoint 设置为可以编辑的 waypoint，
it's saying GPX waypoint is not an editable waypoint.
然后它说 GPX waypoint 不是 editable waypoint 。
Ah-hah.
原来是这样啊。
Because we declared Waypoint Edit to be an editable
因为我们定义 waypoint edit 的类型为 editableWaypoint ，
waypoint, which is good, because it edits it, so
这个是没问题点，因为我们需要对它进行编辑，所以用这个类型
it better be.
更为贴切。
And this is a GPX Waypoint, cuz I copied this line of code
这个是GPXWaypoint ，因为我是从这里把代码拷贝过来的，
from up here, where we're looking at the image URL.
这个就是我们之前查看的图像URL部分的，
So really easy fix, though,
所以这个很好修复的。
we'll just set this to be an editable waypoint.
我们这里把它设置为一个可以编辑的航点。
'Kay?
可以把。
Now, this code will not work.
现在这个代码有报错。
Any sharp-eyed people know why this won't work.
你们眼尖的同学肯定一眼就能看出问题在哪。
It's a problem we've had in other prepare for segues.
这个问题就是我们实际上时给另外一个 seguge 做准备工作的。
>> Navigation.
>> Navigation。（导航视图控制器）
>> Bingo. Bonus points over there.
>> 正确，加10分！
If I were Aron, I'd be throwing candy at you at this point.
如果我是 Aron , 我肯定会奖励给一块糖的。
Yes.
没错。
That editable waypoint view controller is
EditableWayViewController是在
inside a navigation controller.
NavigationController 的内部的。
So the destination view controller is gonna be
所以这个跳转过去的目标视图控制器应该是
that navigation controller.
NavigationController 。
So this is not gonna work, cuz this is gonna fail,
所以这段代码不能正确工作，
this as Waypoint finish.
是以传递 waypoint 结束的。
Now, we've dealt with this in the past,
现在我们知道，之前我们已经遇到过这样的问题，
by putting a little if here, whatever.
只要写一小段代码就好了，
It's so common to want to do that,
这是一个非常常见的情况，
that actually I usually add an extension
实际上我通常都会扩展（继承） UIViewController
to UIViewController that does that.
来解决这个问题。
I call it content view controller, and
我就叫它 ContentViewControler ，然后
all it says is if I'm a navigation controller,
它会记录我们是不是在 Navigation Controller 里面，
then return my visible view controller.
如果在的话，就返回实际展示的视图控制器。
Otherwise return myself.
如果不在的话，就返回自己。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a nice little trick.
所以这是一个很方便的小技巧。
You can now, I can send to any view controller,
现在就可以，给我任何的一个View Controller ，
give me the content view controller.
都能返回给我实际内容的 View Controller 。
If you are the content view controller,
如果你就是实际内容的 View Controller ，
you just give me yourself.
你就给我你自己。
If you're a navigation controller,
如果你是一个 Navigation Controller ，
then you give me the visible view controller.
你就给我当前正在展示的 View Controller 。
So this is a really nice little extension to throw in
在你的 APP 开发中，你用了这个小的扩展（继承）之后，在处理
all your apps that are segueing to things that might
segue 跳转的时候，能非常方便的获取实际内容的 ViewController ，
or might not be in navigation controllers.
不用在意它是否在 Navigation Controller 里了。
So I use this by saying destinationViewController.con-
这里我就写上 destinationViewController.con-
tentViewController.
tentViewController ，就可以了。
'Kay?
对吧？
Cuz I added this var to all view controllers.
因为我已经给所有的 View Controller 加上了 var 关键字。
In fact, I can do the same thing up here.
事实上，我是对于这个，我们的图片在这里
With this one, okay, our image one.
做同样的处理的。
So, if we ever put our image, if we were ever transitioning
如果你之前已经放了我们的图片，或是之前之前我们已经改变过图片的显示，
to show the image and it wrapped in a view controller,
它就已经包括在了 View Controller ，
we could do that as well.
我们也可以这样做。
So I almost put this in all of my
所以我把它放到了我所有跳转目标的
destination view controller segues.
View Controller 的 segue。
Why not? Doesn't hurt, okay.
为什么这么做？不会有什么不好的事情，对的。
All right.
没问题。
So now this will work.
好，现在它应该是可以正常运行的了。
Let's go ahead and run.
让我们运行试试看。
Okay, we add, we click, we edit, we go here.
好的，我增加一个，点击，然后编辑，我们到这里了。
Oh, notice now it says dropped.
看下，它说它现在写的是 “dropped”。
Because we prepared it, so
因为我们已经提前为它设置好了，
it knows that it's the one that said drop.
所以它知道它自己应该写上 “dropped” 状态。
So I'm going to change this.
所以我要修改下这个。
Now we'll put back in Golf Course.
然后我现在回到了 Golf Couse 。
It's worse typing it in now that it's going to work.
如果可以继续运行的话，我前面的输入是有问题的。
Course.
Coures。
Okay. And then we could say it's
现在我可以继续输入，
“under the snow, which it was when”
“under the snow, which it was when“
“from this trip.”
”from this trip.”
Okay, so here we are.
好的，现在我们在这里。
We've got this, and we hit done.
我们已经编辑好了，然后点击 done 按钮。
And now when we look at our waypoint, it's edited it.'
现在当我们再看我们的航带你，它已经是编辑好了的。
Kay?
对吧？
All right.
非常好。
Now, let's look at something else.
然后我们再看看其他的。
What's this gonna look like on an iPad?
在iPad上看起来怎么样？
It looks great on iPhone, really nice, okay.
在 iPhone 上看起来真是不错。
But, let's take a look at iPad.
那么，让我们看看在 iPad 上
See what that looks like.
效果是怎么样的吧。
So I have an iPad here.
这里我有一个 iPad 。
It's going to run on that.
在上面直接运行。
All right.
好的。
There we go. There's an iPad.
我们看下，在这个iPad 。
Here's Trax.
这是我们的 APP Trax。
Now Trax is incredible on the iPad because
现在 Trax 看起来在 iPad 上的样子有点“出乎意料”，
it's got such a big screen,
因为它的屏幕太大了。
we can really see all of our stuff very clearly.
我可以清楚的看到所有的内容。
And especially if we click and want to look at an image.
特别是当我点击这里，想看下这个图片，
Wow, we got this really nice screen loading it up here,
哇，这个展示效果真是不错呀，
but, whoa, look at that.
但，哦，看看那里。
So it's a gray.
是灰色的。
So it's actually quite great.
实际上看起来还是不错的。
This is quite a great thing on the iPad.
在 iPad 上看起来效果还是挺不错的。
But there's a problem with the iPad.
但在 iPad 上有一个问题。
Watch this.
看这里。
Let's add.
我们增加一个。
Okay.
好的。
Click on Dropped > Edit.
点击这个然后编辑。
And we've got this humongous thing.
我们会看到一个很搞笑大事情。
I mean there's no way we would ever use that much screen real
我的意思是，我们根本没有办法在这个屏幕分辨率上使用
estate, okay?
它，对吧？
So that's really not an appropriate UI.
所以这不是一个合适 UI 。
Listen to me carefully.
这里注意一下我说的话。
That's not an appropriate UI for an iPad, okay?
这不是一个适应于 iPad 的UI，对吧？
And I know that some of you, who were putting on your final
我知道你们有些人，在准备最后的大作业的时候，
project, oh yeah for breadth, I'm supporting the iPad.
也会考虑到，正在支持 iPad 的展示。
And all you're doing is doing it on iPhone and
现在你现在做的这些，在 iPhone 上看起来都很好，
then hoping that this is okay.
然后希望它在 iPad 上也是好的。
But this is not okay.
但事实上不是这样的。
Okay? This does not look
对吧？这个看起来在 iPad 上展示的
on the iPad.
不合适。
So if you're gonna say I support the iPad, don't try
所以如果你写这个 APP 支持 iPad ，可是“忽悠”不了我们，
and swing this one by us, cuz we're just not gonna buy it.
我们是不会买单的。
Okay, we're gonna write down, doesn't really support iPad.
好吧，我们只是准备这样做，但实际上我们现在还不能支持 iPad 。
All right, so how could we make this UI look more
好吧，那我们想让我们的 UI 能够支持 iPad 该
iPad-esque?
怎么做呢？
Well, there's a couple things we can do.
我们还是要好几件事情。
One is, we could go back to our storyboard and
首先，我们要回到我们的 storyboard
we can change the transition style,
然后改变一下转换的方式。
'kay, of this particular segue way that we have down here.
好的，我们需要这个特殊的 segue 。
Where is it?
在哪里呢？
It's over here.
在这里。
Here it is.
就是它。
If, we can change, it's still modal, but we can change this
这里我们还是把它设置为 modal ，但我们可以改变它的展示样式，
presentation, for example, to be form sheet.
举个例子，改为 form sheet 。
So form sheet, it's iPad only.
这个是只有 iPad 才有的。
This will be ignored if you set this on an iPhone.
如果你在 iPhone 上设置的话，将会被直接忽略。
The Form sheet looks like this, and
Form sheet 看起来是这个样子的，
it's a little better.
看起来好多了。
It's not enough better for your final project,
你最后的大作业应该要比这个好，
but it's a little better.
不过现在这个效果在这里。
So here's what it looks like.
看起来是这样的。
All right, so I'm gonna add one here.
我们会在这里加上一个。
Click on it, edit it.
点击这里，编辑它。
See the Form sheet, at least it's smaller, okay?
看下这个 Form sheet ，它会更小一点，对吧？
So it's a little better.
这样会更好点。
It doesn't look too bad.
看起来还不错。
It's almost good enough.
已经够好的了。
But really what the iPad wants is for
但实际上，iPad 上我们一般都是使用
that to be in a popover, right?
popover（弹出） 的，对吧？
I wanna be able to go here.
我想这里也可以这样做。
And when I click this little thing, I want a small little
当我点击这里时，我想有一个小一点的 popover 出来，
popover that just has the name and info field.
里面包括名字和信息的文本框。
And if I have an image, make space for an image.
如果我有图片的话，就给图片多“留”些地方。
That's the perfect thing for an iPad, okay?
这样在 iPad 上看起来就完美了，对吧？
So let's turn this baby into a popover.
好，然后让我们把它放到 popover 里。
And that's gonna break the heck out of our iPhone one,
这样会让我们在 iPhone 上无法返回。
but we're gonna go back and fix that too, okay?
我们这样要回过头来修复这个问题，可以？
But, first things first, let's make this into a popover.
不过，我们现在最需要的是先把这个改为 popover 。
So, how do we make this into a popover?
那我该怎么做呢？
Well, I'm gonna get rid of this modal segue.
这里我将准备不使用 modal segue 。
So here's the modal segue.
好，这里是 modal segue 。
Let me zoom out so you can see it.
我缩小一点，你们就能看清楚了。
This is the modal segue that segues through this navigation
这个 modal segue 将从 navigation controller
controller over to here.
跳转到这里。
So I'm just going to delete that by hitting delete.
这里我就先选中它，然后删掉。
I'm gonna have to move these over
因为我的屏幕不够大，
closer because I have such a small screen here.
所以这里我不得不先把他们挪得靠近一些。
Then I'm gonna zoom in and then I'm just gonna make a new
然后我把它放大，然后就给可以从这里
segue from here directly to here.
创建一个新的 segue 。
I'm not gonna go through the navigation controller because
这里我是不经过 navigation controller 的，因为我不想
I don't want my popover to
我的 popover 里面的内容有一个
have a navigation controller title bar.
navigation controller 的标题栏。
Totally unnecessary.
因为完全没必要。
It's gonna be nice, sleek, little popover.
这样就好了，漂亮，一个小的 popover 。
So I'm just gonna go directly to here and
我这里直接就跳转到这里，然后以模态的方式
instead of present modally,
直接替换当前展示的内容。
I'm going to do popover presentation here.
我这里是以 popover 的方式进行展示的。
Okay?
懂了吗？
Now when you do a popover, you notice I got an error here.
现在，当我打开 popover ，你会发现这里报错了。
Okay?
对吧？
If I click on this and see what this error is, it says,
我们点开这里看下具体是什么错误，它说
'Popover segue with no anchor'.
“Popover segue with no anchor”
Okay? I've got some frames to
嗯？我已经调整了框架（frame）
adjust here.
在这里
And we have this unreachable scene,
因为这个 navigation controller，所以
because of this navigation controller, but that's okay.
这里是不能操作的区域，但那里是可以的。
It's this popover error with no anchor.
因为没有指定的锚点，所以无法 popover 。
So, what does that mean?
这是什么意思呢？
Well, when you do a popover, the little arrow on
当你要 popover 的时候，这个在popover上的小箭头
the popover has gotta know where to point, okay?
就应该已经知道在哪里展示，对吧？
Sometimes, it points to a bar button.
有些时候，它是指向 bar button 。
And here, I'm gonna have it point to the map view.
这里我们是希望它能指向我们的 map view。
More specifically,
更进一步说，
I'm gonna have it point to the little pin.
我是希望它能够指向这个小的标识。
Okay?
对吧？
So if we don't specify that then a popover can't work.
这里如果我们没有指明的话，就无法正常进行popover。
So how do we specify that?
那我们该怎么指明呢？
How do we specify where, when this popover wants to popover
当从这个 view controller 要 popover 的时候，该怎么
from this view controller, it shows up?
指明是从哪里？
Well, one part of it we can do with dragging.
对的，我们需要先通过拖动的方法来完成。
You see right here, in the inspector,
看下这里， 在 inspector（检查器）。
I've inspected this segue right here.
我已经在这里设置过这个 segue 。
I clicked right on here.
我在这里点击。
You can see that it says anchor.
你就能看到这里有一个 anchor （锚点）。
It says drag to select an anchor.
然后就直接拖到这个锚点。
Okay, well, I'm just gonna drag over to my map view,
对对，我从我们的 map view 拖过去的。
oops, except for I need to zoom in.
哦，我想我需要放大一些。
Okay? So,
好吧，
I'm just going to select the segue.
现在我们选中了这个 segue 。
I'm gonna drag to my map view.
拖到我的 map view。
And it says, okay, map view.
对，是的，map view。
Great.
好极了。
You're good to go.
现在就可以了。
And it game me no more error.
已经没有报错信息了。
Except for this is not gonna work either because
不过还是不能正常工作，
I have to say where in the map view I want this to work from.
因为我没有设置从 map view 的哪个位置展示 popover的内容。
If I don't say where, it's gonna try and
如果我不写是哪里，它就会从
point it to the edge of the map view itself,
map view 的边缘开始。
which is gonna be off screen, which is useless.
这样就到屏幕的外面了，看不到，也就没用了。
I need to specify a little rectangle inside.
我需要在里面指定一个小些的区域。
So how do I do that?
那我该怎么做呢？
Where do I specify that little rectangle?
我在哪里指定这个小些的区域（矩形）？
And the answer is it's exactly where we specify
我们必须要配置 popover 的具体
anything having to do with configuring a popover.
在哪个位置。
Okay and we have already done this in this class but
好的，我们已经把代码写完了，但我们还是忘了些事情
you have probably forgotten, but for
我想你们大多数人在最后的大作业中都会
your final project many of you are gonna do popovers.
用到 popovers 吧，这里就是提醒一下你们
So here is something to remember where you
这些地方不要忘了，
set things for popover, and
你需要对 popover 进行设置。
that is in the prepare for segue for that popover segue.
也就是需要对 popover segue 进行预先的设置。
Okay, specifically I'm gonna do it right down here, and
好的，这里我就准备在这里写了，
you wanna get the popovers presentation controller.
我们是希望得到一个 popover presentation controller 。
Okay? And you get the proper
对吧？然后想得到
presentation controller just by asking the,
这个 controller 是需要通过名称，
make sure is it the right name for
这里我们给它命名为 PPC，
these things that I call that PPC, I think I did yeah.
这样就可以了。
You just ask the thing that you're presenting,
你只需要问需要展示的控制器，
give me your popover presentation controller.
让它给你 popover presentation controller 就可以了。
Okay?
对吧？
But you probably want to if let this, because you want
但你可能会想到，如果我不是 popover 的话，
your code to work even if it's not in a popover.
我也希望我的代码能够正常工作。
If we change this back to be modal,
这里如果我把它改为 modal 方式的返回，
we'd still want it to work.
它就应该也能正常工作了。
If you're not in a popover presentation this
如果你不是 pop presentation 的话，这里就会返回
will return nil, so you won't be doing the code in here.
nil，所以这里你就需要写一些代码来处理。
So this code is only going to happen if this segue is
这些代码时针对这个 segue 是跳转到 popover controller的才
popover controlled.
有用。
So popover presentation controller, okay, if you look
至于这个 popover presentation controller ，如果你看过
at it in the documentation you can see that it's got, oops,
文档的话 ，哦，
that's not a very good link to that is it?
这个链接有问题？
Oh, maybe it doesn't return that.
可能它不能返回了。
Wait a minute. [INAUDIBLE] Okay,
等一下，好了，是这个
PopoverPresentationController.
PopoverPresentationController。
You can see it's got some things here like that source
你可以看到，相关内容的这些
view that we wired up.
介绍的。
Okay, it's also got sourceRect.
这里还有 getSourceRect。
That's the rectangle inside the source view.
是指可以获取内部 source view 的显示区域。
Or you can have a bar button item.
或是你也可以在这增加一个 bar button item 。
If you have a bar button item, you don't need both of these.
如果你已经有了 bar button item ，你就不需要。
We've, so it's kind of either/or.
这是一个可以选择的。
And also, it's got a delegate, which we're gonna use to
另外，我们还看到有一个 delegate ，我们可以
control our adaptive behavior and a few other things.
使用它来做一些事情。
But, so that's what you can configure in
这些就是我们可以在 popoverPresentationController
the popoverPresentationController.
可以设置的内容。
So let's do that sourceRect.
好，让我们先来设置一下 sourceRect 。
Okay.
好。
So the sourceRect equals.
让这个 sourceRect 等于
We want this, basically a rectangle for
这个 annotation view 的类型是
that annotation view so I'm going to say here,
MK annotation view，
the sender as an MK annotation view.
这里我们的显示区域就是针对这个 view 的。
Okay, so sender, remember is this sender to the prepare for
好的，这里是否还记得这个 sender 就是 我们传递给 annotation view
segue which we passed the annotation view as the sender.
用来设置 seguge 的那个。
Okay?
对吧？
So the sender is the pin that's causing all this trouble.
所以这个 sender 就是那个小的标识，也是它造成了这一切的麻烦。
And I added a nice method to that called popover SourceRect
这里我准备增加一个方法，命名叫。
for coordinate point.
popoverSourceRectForCoordinatePoint
And you just give it a point, coordinate point.
这里你给定坐标上的点。
And so let's calculate that point.
然后我们来计算这个点。
I'll show you that method in a second.
我下面就会来给具体写这个方法。
So we're going to let the coordinate point.
我们首先让这个坐标下的点。
We're going to calculate the coordinate point by getting
我们会通过计算得到这个点的坐标转换为
the annotations coordinate and
在注释视图上的坐标，我们是通过
using the map view to convert it.
map view 来完成这个转换。
So mapView.convertCoordinate,
所以就写 mapView.convertCoordinate，
and the coordinate is the way points coordinate.
然后这个坐标就是 way point 的坐标。
And we're going to convert it to a point in the map view.
我们将会把这个点在 map view 里进行转换。
Alright, so here I'm just getting the point of our pin,
好的，这里我们是可以得到我们的这个小标志的坐标，
where our pin is on the map, and
那我们的坐标在地图的哪里？
then I'm asking the notation view, please give me
然后我需要问 notation view， 请给我一个区域，在你的坐标系
a rectangle that would be good for a popover to point at.
要能刚好可以放下
At that coordinate point.
我的 popover 的视图。
And this code, this popover thing, is right here.
这段代码，在这个 popover ，在这里。
And it's really simple, really.
要做的是非常简单，真的。
It just gets the width and height of our frame,
只是需要得到我们的 frame 的宽度和高度。
our little pin views frame.
是我们这个小的标识的 frame 。
And then it offsets it by the calloutOffset and
然后设置通过 calloutOffset和 centerOffset 设置
the centerOffset.
偏移量。
Don't worry too much about those.
不用担心太多。
But that's all it does.
这样就可以了。
So it's basically just putting a frame around itself so
只需要最基本的设置一个 frame，然后我们就
that we can have the popover.
可以看到 popover。
I just didn't wanna put that code in here and
我是不想把这些代码放到这里，怕影响你们的理解，
mess it up for you, but that's all it does.
但这样其实就好了。
Now, we have this popover source rec.
现在我们已经有了 popover source rect 。（展示区域）
Let's see what this looks like.
让我们看看效果。
This is not gonna quite be what we want, but
这看起来不完全是我们希望的，但我们已经可以看到
we're getting there.
它们了。
All right, [SOUND] Here we go,' kay?
好的，接着，怎么？
I'm gonna long press to drop.
我们长按后然后松开。
We're gonna edit it.
我们要编辑它。
And we got a crash.
哦，我们的程序崩溃了。
Okay. And, so why does this crash?
好吧，为什么它会崩溃？
It's because we forgot to set our segue identifier for
这是因为我们忘了把我们的segue的标识符设置为
the popover to edit waypoints, okay?
popover to edit waypoints，对吧？
Probably you've all seen this.
你们已经可以看到这个报错。
No segue with identifier error.
No segue with identifier error。
That's easy to fix.
这个很好被修复。
Let's go back to our storyboard.
让我们回到我们的 storyboard 。
Get our segue inspected.
然后看下我们的 segue 的检查器
And sure enough, look at that.
确定了，看这里。
Edit Wavepoint.
Edit Wavepoint。
All right, sometimes it's good when I forget to do
对的，有些时候看起来是没有问题的，我们忘了做一些事情
things like that because you get to see common things.
这是因为我们已经把一些基本的设置完成了。
That's a common thing to do, is to forget.
做完这些基本的设置，会忘记的。
Either to have the name be different or
比如应该设置不同的名字，或是
you forget to put it in entirely.
忘了把它全部修改好。
All right, so now, here we go, like that, and Edit.
好，现在，让我们在看看效果，这里，编辑。
And we've got a popover.
好，我们可以看到 popover 了。
Whoo!
哎！
It doesn't look very good, though.
看起来还是不太对。
Okay.
好吧。
So, it's kind of close, but it's gigantic still, and
已经很接近老，但它实在是太大了，
the whole point of this is to not use so
这个（弹出框）并没有合理的
much darn screen real estate.
使用屏幕（没有显示合适的大小）。
So why is that happening?
为什么会这样？
Well, that's because we do nothing to tell the system
好吧，这是因为我们没有告诉
what we would like the content size to be here.
我们内容的大小。
And if you remember, the last time we did popovers,
如果你还记得，我们最后设置 did popovers 的地方，
we actually overrode the.
我实际是重写（overrode）
Property preferred content size and
preferred content size 这个属性，然后是返回
return calculated content size.
计算后的 content size 。
Here I'm going to do it a different way.
这里，我准备用另外一种方法。
I'm gonna actually set the preferred content size.
我会直接设置好这个 preferred conten size。
So I'm doing the same thing.
好，我们来做吧。
I'm just gonna set it, because it's a var.
我要来设置它，因为它是一个 var 。
I can set it, it's a settable var.
我可以直接设置它，
I don't have to override it.
我不需要直接重写（override）他。
So I'm just gonna set it to a size.
所以我会直接设置它的大小。
And so, what kind of size would be good there?
那么，这里应该设置多大的会比较合适？
Let me make some more space.
让我们先多空出一些位置。
We're still doing all this inside this popover-specific
我们来在popover的对应的代码来处理
code.
这件事。
A good size for that would be, height-wise,
我们需要这样一个合适的大小，高度时自动适应的，
it would be if I just let the auto layout do it.
这个部分可以通过 auto layout 实现。
Wouldn't it be cool if I could just find out what
如果我们能通过 auto layout 之后最小的 size 的话
the auto layout thought the smallest size was?
那就最好不过了。
Turns out, you can do that.
那么事实是，这是可以做到的。
Watch this, let minimum size equal
看这里，let minimum size 等于
the view controller's view.
这个视图控制的视图。
I'm just gonna smash down the view controller view as much
我就准备尽量把这个视图控制器下的视图
as possible.
压缩到最小。
The name of the method is called
这个方法的名字就叫做
systemLayoutFittingSize.
systemLayoutFittingSize。
And it takes a size, and
传入的是一个 size ，
that size is the size it's gonna try to fit into.
这个 size 就是我们准备调整的。
And there's really two choices here.
这里有两个选择可以考虑。
One is, fit it into as small a space as possible,
一个是，调整到一个尽量小多区域里，
or fit it into as big a space as possible, okay?
或是调整到一个尽量大的区域里，对吧？
So I'm gonna go for small as possible,
这里我是准备要一个尽量小的区域，
cuz I want this thing to be small.
因为我想需要内容能够紧凑些。
So that UILayoutFittingSizeCompress.
所以这里：UILayoutFittingSizeCompress 。
See, there's expanded and compressed.
看这里有 expanded（扩展） 和 compressed（压缩）。
So I want the compressed size.
我需要一个压缩后的大小。
So this is gonna give me the minimum size that that
它就返回给我一个最小的size， 然后视图控制器也是可以
view controller can be by using Auto Layout.
通过 Auto Layout 进行布局。
Okay, which is really awesome.
好吧，这个简直太棒了。
This is what the table U cells are using to size,
这就是我们在表格的单元格里自动获得内容
get the heights automatically with a layout.
高度的方法。
It's a really, really great feature.
这真是一个非常非常好的特性。
Now, I don't actually want it to be the minimum size in
现在，我并不需要在宽度方面
width, though.
也是最小的。
Because I wanna have some room for
因为我需要多预留出一部分位置，让用户可以
the person to type in the name and the info that they want.
输入名字和相关的内容。
So I'm going to pick a size.
我下面来设置这个 size 。
It's going to be a constant in my app.
在我的APP里我将定一个常量。
So, I'm going to set my preferred content size,
我先设置我的 preferred content size ,
equal CGSize.
等于 CGSize。
And the width I want is going to be this constant,
然后我希望宽度是一个常量。
constants, whoops, width, constants dot, what did I
常量，哦，宽度，直接用 constants 点（出来）
call it here, yeah, edit waypoint pop-over width, okay?
可以看到提示，对，edit waypoint pop-over width ，对吧？
And that the height is gonna be the minimumSize.
然后高度就是 minimumSize.height ，对吧？
The height, okay?
So I'm using the minimumSize for the height, but
我这里用minimumSize的高度，同时
I'm picking this, which I've set to be 320, which
我处理的时候，它的宽度已经被设置为320，这是一个默认值。
is pretty standard width, and a pretty good width.
这个宽度非常好。
That's probably about the width of that is now.
因为这恰好就是我们当前的宽度。
But by setting preferred content size,
但是在设置首选内容区域的大小时，
that tells the pop-over machinery
就可以自动计算和
to make the pop-over be this size if possible.
设置 pop－over 的区域大小。
It's only preferred, it might not be possible,
这只是优先，但不是必须的。
cuz the geometry of other views might get in the way,
因为其他的视图可能会相互有影响，
can't do it, but this is,
可能就无法设置，这种情况下，
it's going to try to make it this if it can't.
就会继续尝试设置，
And usually, it can't.
一般情况下，它是不能的 。
So, let's go see how this works.
那就让我们看下效果到底如何。
Okay, here we go.
好，来，我们看看。
Long press.
长按。
Top.
上面。
Edit.
编辑。
Oh awesome okay, and now we can edit this right into
哦，太好来，现在我们就可以刚好在这里进行编辑
place here, golf course,
golf course，
you know, foo.
你们知道的 ，foo。
Okay, and it's editing it on the fly, editing as do, so
好的，现在可以直接进行编辑，
if I click away and
如果我点击离开，然后
then click back, I get golf course still, okay?
点击返回，我这里看到的还是 golf course ，对吧？
And, again, I can always go back, edit it again.
然后，我再回来继续编辑。
So this is really looking good.
看起来非常好。
It's not quite perfect.
但还不是特别完美。
It's kind of, if you look at the arrow that points down,
这里，你看箭头指向的这里，
it looks like it's kind of see-through,
这里应该能够透过去看到下面，
but the thing is white.
但现在这里是白的。
So, there's no reason that
这是因为 pop-over 需要这里
this pop-over needs to be white.
是白色的。
It'd be really cool if it kind of, you could see back,
如果我们可以透过这里看到后面的内容，
see-through it a little bit to what's behind.
这样的话一定很酷。
Wouldn't that be kind of more iPhone-ish and kind of iOS-y.
这样的话看起来更想 iOS 自带的程序。
So let's do that.
好，我们继续来做。
That's trivial to do that.
这些都是些常用的做法。
Let's just go into our storyboard and
我们先去到我们的 storyboard ，然后到
have our view up here, our little.
我们的视图这里，我们这个
Waypoint editing view be transparent.
waypoint 编辑视图是透明的。
So I'm just going to select this thing.
我们先选中它，
Instead of its background being white right here,
然后你可以看到它的背景色变为了白色。
I'm going to set it to be clear, okay?
我将把它设置为 clear ，可以？
So that's going to fix that.
这样就可以修复我们前面的问题了。
So let's go see what that looks like.
好，那让我们看下效果如何。
All right, and click Edit, okay?
好的，点击编辑，怎么样？
So you can see,
看到了吧，
I don't know how well you can see it in that.
我想你们之前肯定没有见过这么好的吧。
It might be washed out there, but I can, actually, see,
这里可以看到背后的，是的，你看
kind of, a blurred mountains there, scenery behind, okay?
一座山在这里，在这个风景点后面，对吧？
And it, also, just kinda looks better,
是的，这样看起更好点，
the text fields stand out a little more.
这样 text field 也显得明显了。
It's all, just looks a lot better.
这样就看起来更好了。
Okay, now, there's only problem with all of this,
好，现在就只剩下一个问题了，
which is the iPhone.
就是在 iPhone 下的展示效果。
Okay?
对吧？
Let's see what this looks like on iPhone.
让我们看看在 iPhone 下效果到底如何。
Here it is.
这里，
Nice. Drop one.
好的，选这个。
Ooh, yeah, edit.
哦，好的，编辑。
Look, yeah.
看！
Okay.
好的。
So that looked absolutely terrible.
这个看起来是太糟糕了。
We lost our done button because we took it out of that
因为我们把我们的 done 按钮移出了 navigation controller，
navigation controller.
我们没有看到我们的 done 按钮。
And it's got this background,
所以只看到了是背景，
just black, there's nothing there.
就是一个黑色的，然后没有任何东西。
What's going on here?
那我们下面该怎么做？
Well, let's try to fix this iPhone thing.
好，让我们来继续修复这个问题。
One thing we can fix is that black.
首先，我们得修复这个只看到黑色背景这个问题。
The reason that that's coming black,
出现这个问题的原因是，默认的 modal 展示的样式
is because the default modal presentation style
都是全屏，也就是说，
is full screen, which means, take over the whole screen.
会占据整个屏幕的显示区域。
And it expects you to draw in the whole screen.
也就是说它希望你以全屏幕作为显示区域。
So it's just leaving that area black,
所以这里只保留了一个黑色区域。
it's expecting you're gonna draw in that.
它就是希望你可以在这里进行绘图。
There's another kind of style which is over full-screen,
这里还有另外一个样式叫做 over full-screen 。
which just means draw on top of whatever is behind.
意思就是在背景层的上面进行绘图。
So anything that shows through,
所以当前显示的任何东西，你都会看到
you'll see what's behind.
它们被显示到下面。
And this is what alerts are using, things like that.
这种方式是 alert 用的方式，
Even the pop-over was using that, it was blurring it, but
如果 pop-over 用这种方式，就会模糊掉下面的内容，但是
it was still doing that.
它也会把内容置于下层。
So how do we get that to happen?
那我们该如何做呢？
Okay, well, to do that,
好，我们是可以这样做，
we actually need to use the pop-over's delegate,
我们需要使用 pop-over 的 delegate ,
which we did before.
我们之前也过的。
So I'm going to set the pop-over
我们这里把 pop-over controller的 delegate
controller's delegate here to be myself, okay?
设置为我们的自己，对吧？
That means I need to go up here, and say, that I am a,.
这就意味着，我们需要在这里写上，
UI PopoverPresentationController-
Delegate.
Delegate 。
Be careful here not to say, UIPopover Controller Delegate,
注意这里，不是写 UIPopover Controller Delegate
It's PresentationController.
这里是 PresentationController。
That thing is old, okay?
之前那个已经是旧的了。
It's deprecated even.
已经被标记为过期了。
So, it's this one you want, the long one,
所以这里你就需要用这个长的，
PopoverPresentationController- Delegate.
PopoverPresentationController- Delegate。
And once I'm the delegate,
一旦我是作为 delegate 。
now I can control that adaptation behavior.
我就可以控制这个 adaptation 的行为。
So why is that thing showing up
这就是当它目前显示的方式是modal，
modal like that when we have it to be a popover?
而需要展示为popover的时候，
Okay, we changed it to be a popover,
我们就可以直接通过 delegate 把它改为 popover 的原因。
why the heck is it showing up modal?
为什么就可以展示为 modal ？
Well, that's because of this adaptation,
对，就是因为这个 adaptation ，
okay, where the system is adapting to the fact that you
好吧，就是这里系统可以根据实际的情况进行适配，你在 iPhone 不应该用
don't usually show popovers on the phone.
popovers 进行展示。
You show things full-screen modal.
你应该使用全屏幕的 modal 方式展示。
So it's adapting.
这就是适配。
So now that we're the delegate, let's go ahead and
现在我们是 delegate ，我们就可以为展示的这个 controller
implement the adaptive presentations style for
实现这个适配的展示样式
presentation controller, delegate method.
的代理方法。
Thank God for escape completion there.
谢天谢地，我们总算快做完了。
And all we need to do here is return the style, so
我们只是需要在这里返回 style，这里我们将要
the modal presentation style I'm gonna return,
返回 modal presentation style 。
instead of fullscreen, is, overFullscreen.
将 fullscreen 替换为 overFullscreen。
Oops, not over [INAUDIBLE] overFullscreen.
哦，不对， 不是 overFullscreen 。
Okay, so let's see what that did.
好的，让我们看下我们的成果。
It's going to make it a little better, not a lot better,
将会有一点改进，不过不是很大的改进。
but a little better, okay?
总是有点改进，对吧？
Here we go. Now,
好，我们继续，现在
at least we don't have the black, okay?
至少我们看到的不是一片黑了，对吧？
So we can see through, still not so hot.
我们能看到，还不是我们想看到的。
We need that done button back for one thing,
我们需要的一个 done 按钮，可以返回，
without that done button we're done, okay?
没有这个 done 按钮，我们就没法返回了，对吧？
So let's get that done button back.
好，现在让我们把这个 done 按钮“弄”回来。
And I'm going to do that by implementing another pop over
我会通过实现另外一个 pop over 的代理方法
delegate method here which is called, I don't remember what
我现在具体记不得它的名字
the thing is even called, oh yes, presentation.
哦，对对，presentation.
It's this one right here,
就是这个，
viewControllerForAdapterPresentationStyle, okay?
viewControllerForAdapterPresentationStyle。
So this one right here is saying give me a view
这就是我们的视图控制器需要对视图进行
controller to display this thing when I adapt, okay?
适配所需要的方法，对吧？
So what I'm going to do is,
这里我就需要，
I'm going to give it a navigation controller, and
给它一个 navigation controller ，然后说用
tell it to use that instead.
这个来替换
So I'm just gonna say return UINavigationController.
所以这里是要写返回 UINavigationController。
The root view of the navigation controller wants to
这个 navigation controller 的 根视图（root view）
be the thing I'm presenting, which I can get from
就是要展示的控制器，我们可以通过传给我们的参数
this presentation controller argument that's passed to me.
presentation controller 来获得。
That's just controller.presentedViewContr-
只要写 controller.presentedViewController
oller.
就可以来
ViewController, okay?
对吧？
So that's it.
这样就好了。
So let's see what happens now.
让我们看看现在的情况如何。
All right, we're here, we go here, we go here,
好，我们在这里，然后继续，
oh much better.
哦，比之前好多了。
Now we have done, it still kind of looks terrible, but
现在我们有了 done 按钮，但看起来样子不太好，但至少我们
we have done.
已经有了。
So we can say done, oh, excellent, okay.
我们可以说搞定了，太好了。
So now, what are we gonna do to fix this see-through thing?
那么接下来，我们该怎么实现可以透过 pop－over 看到下面内容？
Well, I could just make it white again,
好，我们可以先让它变成白色先，
because now I'm returning the thing here, that view for
因为这里我们返回的内容，这个视图时
controller for adapter present thing.
适配后的控制器的视图。
I'm returning the whole thing, I can do anything I want.
我将返回全部内容，这样我就可以做任何我想做的。
But what I'm gonna use this to take advantage of is use
这里我准备先利用下这个机会给你们展示一下
this chance to show you visual effects like blur.
各种视觉效果的使用，比如 blur 效果。
Because we want really the same thing we had on the iPad,
因为这里我们也有一个刚刚在 iPad 上实现的效果模糊效果，
where the pop-over comes up and it's kind of, you can see
就是当 pop-over 出来之后，
the background through, but it's a little blurred.
你可以看到它下面的内容，但是稍微有点模糊的
We're going to do the same thing here, okay?
这里其实我们是做的同样一件事，对吧？
It's going to come up, it's going to be white, but
当它出现的时候，它会变成白色，
a little blur we can see what's in the background.
但我们可以看到它的背景是稍微有点模糊。
So how do we do that?
我们该怎么做呢？
To do that, we, okay,
这么做，来吧。
the way the visual effects work is very simple.
设置 visual effects 的方法非常简单。
It's just a view, okay, a visual effect view,
只需要这里，对一个 view ， 对 ，visual effect view
and that view looks what's behinds it, what's behind it,
然后这个视图就看起来是放在后面的，看起来
looks at what is behind it, and blurs it, and
像在后面的，然后是模糊的，
then draws that as itself.
它也是自己负责绘制自己的。
It's as simple as that, okay?
这个够简单了吧，对吧？
It's just, looks what behind you in the view hierarchy,
这里，可以看到在你的 view hierarchy 来看到在后面的，
even if that's other views, or I don't care what it is,
甚至是有其他视图，都不需要在乎它们，
it looks at it, creates white or even a dark color and
只是需要设置为白色或是黑色，然后模糊掉，
then blurs it, and now that's what it draws.
现在它们就可以自己绘制自己了。
So all we need to do to make this blur happen is
所以我们需要在 navigation controller 的 view hierarchy
put a visual effects view right at the top
后面的内容都绘制好之后，然后最顶层的
of the navigation controller's view hierarchy
地方增加这个 visual effects ，将显示区域
behind everything that it draws.
模糊化。
Okay, right at the top.
好，在最顶部。
And we know how to insert something at the top of
我们是知道我们在 view hierarchy 中是从顶部插入
the view hierarchy, right?
内容的，对吧？
We just put it at index zero in the subviews list.
我只需要在 subviews 列表中的索引为0的地方处理就可以了。
It'll be right in the back.
就刚好是最后面的。
Okay, and everything else will be in front.
然后其他内容都是在前面的。
Now, if I put it right in the back of the navigation
然后我把它放回到 navigation controller 里面，
control, the thing that's behind the visual effect view
在它后面显示 visual effect 的视图
is gonna be that map view.
就是 map view 。
Because it's clear and so,
因为这个很清楚，
we look back and whoa, there's map view there.
我们看下一下，这里有一个 map view 。
So it's gonna blur that, that's exactly what we want.
它会被模糊化，这就是我们希望的。
All right, so to do this we just need to say I'm gonna
所以，这里我们就是需要
let nav con equal this.
让 nav con 等于这里。
Okay, so there's your navigation controller.
这里已经有了 navigation controller 。
And then I'm gonna say let a visualEffectView equal
这里我接着让 visualEffectView 等于
UIVisualEffectView.
UIVisualEffectView。
Okay, that's this view that does what I was talking about.
这个 view 就是我们前面刚刚说过的。
And it wants to know what effect you wanna apply.
它需要知道你要让它实现什么样的效果。
There's a couple of effects, vibrancy and blur.
这里有很多效果，比如 vibrancy 和 blur。
So we're gonna do blur.
这里我们需要的是 blur 。
So I want the blur effect.
我们要的是 blur effect 。
And the blur effect I want is with style, extra light.
对于blur effect 这个style ，我们还希望有 extra light。
So, extra light is a very light colored thing,
extra light 是一个指一个浅的颜色，
almost white, with the blur in there.
和blur在一起，接近白色。
There's also dark and just light.
这里也有浅黑色的。
Then I'm going to set the visual effect views frame
我这里准备把 visual effect views的框架设置为
equal to the navCon's view.bounds.
navCon的视图的bounds（显示区域）。
So I want to totally fill the top level of the navigation
这是因为我想能够完全覆盖住整个 navigation
controller.
controller 。
And then I'm just going to add this
然后我就把它加入到我的 navigation controller
thing to the view hierarchy of my navigation controller.
这里的 view hierarchy 。
VisualEffectView, and I'm gonna put it at index zero.
我准备把这个 VisualEffectView 放倒索引值为0的位置。
Okay which means it's in the back of absolutely everything.
And then I'm going to return the navigation controller.
然后我就可以返回 navigation controller 。
Okay, here we go, all right.
好，让我们看下效果吧。
Click.
点击
Boom.
咚
Edit.
编辑。
Blur.
模糊的。
So this looks pretty good.
看起来非常好。
This actually looks slightly better than being all white,
这里看起来比全都是白色的效果要好些了。
it kind of gives users a little bit of context to where
至少能够给用户一点信息就是他现在哪里。
they were.
Still works perfectly fine here.
到现在我们做的都很好。
Our favorite golf course, it's under the snow, okay?
我最喜欢的 golf course ，it's under the snow ，对吧？
Hit done, go here.
点击 done ，继续。
It's working.
运行的很好。
And just to make sure that we didn't break anything on
这里我们还需要确认我们在 iPad 上也还是像以前一样，
the iPad, let's go run it over there one more time.
没有被影响到什么，那我就让我们再运行一次。
Now, we can't possibly have broken anything here,
好的，我们没有破坏任何东西。
because, famous last words, but [LAUGH] we can't,
有名的最后一句话，但是我们没有（幽默的的说法），
because all we changed was the adaptive stuff.
因为我们所有的修改都是在适配后的内容上。
And on the iPad, it doesn't adapt,
而在 iPad 上，我们没有进行适配，
because the iPad is regular in both width and
因为 iPad 是一个规则的宽度和高度，
height, it never has to adapt to being in a compact space.
就不需要在对应压缩显示区域后的适配问题。
So here we go.
好，我们继续。
Click on here.
点击这里。
Bingo.
太棒了。
Okay, so that's it.
好的，就是这样。
Perfect timing.
时间刚刚好。
Almost.
差不多吧。
Next time, we will pick up with slides that tell you how
下次，我们将先通过幻灯片讲一些关于
to do the camera.
摄像头的内容。
And then we'll enhance our editor here to let you take
然后我们会继续增强我们编辑器的功能，让你能够通过
a picture.
它拍一张照片。
And we'll enhance our popover right here,
同时，我们也会增强我们的 popover 的功能。
to show the picture right in the pop-over, okay?
能够支持直接显示图片。
And then after that we'll talk a little bit about
在这之后，我们会再谈一些关于持久化的内容，
persistence, and we'll save the image in the file system.
我们将会把图片保存我们的文件系统里。
Show you how to do that.
然后你们会知道该如何做到的。
Okay, thank you very much.
好的，非常感谢。
I'm here if you have any questions as usual.
和平时一样，如果你们有问题可以来问我。
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
想了解更多，请访问 standford.edu 。